导演：奥利弗·斯通
"The movie will begin in five moments"
这是我的故事，你知道吗？
the mindless voice announced.
那是一群充满焦虑的年轻人...
"All those unseated will await the next show."
在生活的泥淖里挣扎呐喊的声音
让我们缓缓的 无精打采地进入演唱大厅在生活的泥淖里挣扎呐喊的声音
让我们缓缓的 无精打采地进入演唱大厅
We filed slowly, languidly into the hall.
在生活的泥淖里挣扎呐喊的声音让我们缓缓的 无精打采地进入演唱大厅
让我们缓缓的 无精打采地进入演唱大厅在生活的泥淖里挣扎呐喊的声音
We filed slowly, languidly into the hall.
在生活的泥淖里挣扎呐喊的声音
The auditorium was vast and silent.
周围的一切既悠远又宁静
当我们表情阴沉地入座之后 掌声响起来周围的一切既悠远又宁静
当我们表情阴沉地入座之后 掌声响起来
As we seated and were darkened, the voice continued.
周围的一切既悠远又宁静当我们表情阴沉地入座之后 掌声响起来
当我们表情阴沉地入座之后 掌声响起来周围的一切既悠远又宁静
As we seated and were darkened, the voice continued.
周围的一切既悠远又宁静
"The program for this evening is not new.
今晚的节目并不新颖
今晚的节目并不新颖今晚的节目并不新颖
"The program for this evening is not new.
今晚的节目并不新颖
You've seen this entertainment through and through.
你或许已经一遍又一遍地欣赏过它
你或许已经一遍又一遍地欣赏过它你或许已经一遍又一遍地欣赏过它
You've seen this entertainment through and through.
你或许已经一遍又一遍地欣赏过它
You've seen your birth, your life and death.
你将从中体味到你的生命 生活与死亡
你将从中体味到你的生命 生活与死亡你将从中体味到你的生命 生活与死亡
You've seen your birth, your life and death.
你将从中体味到你的生命 生活与死亡
You might recall all of the rest.
回忆起所有的休止符
Did you have a good world when you died?
当你死去的时候
当你死去的时候当你死去的时候
Did you have a good world when you died?
当你死去的时候
Enough to base a movie on?"
能够拥有一个美好的空间吗？
能够拥有一个美好的空间吗？能够拥有一个美好的空间吗？
Enough to base a movie on?"
能够拥有一个美好的空间吗？
Hey, Jim, it's your birthday, man.
嘿，吉姆，今天不是你的生日吗？
What do you say we finish this another night?
我们下次再干吧
Turn the lights down a little bit more, will you, Jay?
约翰，我的歌怎么样？
Hey, man. How come the Doors aren't in on this?
嘿，伙计 乐队用门这个名字你看行不行？
No music. No Doors. Come on, let's roll.
别提音乐也别提门了，到此为止
Rolling.
好了
ls everybody in?
人人都在吗？
The ceremony is about to begin.
仪式就要开始了
Let me tell you about heartache...
让我来告诉你如何生活
以及上帝的消失 片名：大门让我来告诉你如何生活
以及上帝的消失 片名：大门
and the loss of God.
片名：大门以及上帝的消失 片名：大门
以及上帝的消失片名：大门
and the loss of God.
片名：大门
Wandering, wandering in hopeless night.
在毫无希望的夜晚四处徘徊
Out here, in the perimeter, there are no stars.
让我来告诉你们 在这个世界上所有的明星中
Out here, we is stoned, immaculate.
谁才是奇才
"1949年，新墨西哥"谁才是奇才
"1949年，新墨西哥"
lt's beautiful. Look at those big, puffy clouds.
我们都在这尘世间酩酊大醉
Hey, Jimmy. Wake up. Look at the clouds.
嘿，吉米，醒醒
Come on. Wake up.
吉米，醒醒
What's going on?
这些人怎么啦？
l don't know.
Officer, what happened? Can we help?
先生，我们来得真巧，需要帮忙吗？
No, sir. We've got everything under control.
哦，不，你们过去吧
Just a dream, Jimmy.
太奇怪了
That's all it is. lt's just a dream
这一切对我来说太奇怪了
"1965年，加州威尼斯海滩"
Waiting for the medicine.
去喝点酒吗？
On your finger.
我等了很久了
Wait here. Don't go.
好，我一会儿再来
l'll be right here.
好的
You got a problem with doors?
你怎么不从门走？
Waste of time.
就这么一次
l followed you from the beach.
我一直从海滩跟你到这儿
You followed me?
跟着我？
- Why? - 'Cause...
-为什么？ -因为...
you're the one.
你知道为什么
Maybe you should meet my old man.
或许你该成为我的情人
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
- Mine's Jim. - Pam.
-我叫吉姆 -我叫帕姆拉
Who the hell was that?
你刚才和谁在说话？
l have no idea.
我也不太清楚
Nietzsche said...
米切尔说过...
"All great things must first wear terrifying and monstrous masks..
所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的
"加州大学洛杉矶分校电影学校"所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的
"All great things must first wear terrifying and monstrous masks..
"加州大学洛杉矶分校电影学校" 我们用人类的心理所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的
"加州大学洛杉矶分校电影学校" 我们用人类的心理
in order to inscribe themselves...
所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的"加州大学洛杉矶分校电影学校" 我们用人类的心理
所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的
in order to inscribe themselves...
来描述它的自身所有伟大的东西起先 总是以可怕荒谬的面目出现的
来描述它的自身
on the hearts of humanity."
我们用人类的心理来描述它的自身
我们用人类的心理
Listen, children...
听着，孩子们
to the sound of the Nuremberg night.
在这座大城市的夜晚
ln a seance...
这个...
the shaman leads a sensuous panic.
擅于煽动群众情绪的领导者...
He acts like a madman. A professional hysteria.
引起了一场极端的恐怖
Have you ever seen God?
他的行为就像一个疯子
Mandala?
像一个内行的...
A symmetrical angel.
歇斯底里者
We got our final vision by clap.
你们都已经看到过
Columbus' groin got filled with green death.
它所造成的痛苦伤害以至死亡
- l touched her thigh... - This film is weak.
你们看到这最后一幕了吗？
and death smiled.
你们的热情就快死去了
Hey, Morrison. Fuck them, man.
莫里森，该死的人
lt's great. lt's nonlinear, it's poetry.
再没有比这更可怕的了
lt's everything good art stands for.
这是一首史诗，你写得真棒
This world, a monster of energy.
这个世界，巨大的能量
Without beginning, Without end.
你们拥有开始，你们也拥有结束
Likewise, without increase or income.
直到一无所有 这是非常正确的方式
Disclosing nothing.
我们从中获取了印象和收益
This world.
这个世界
This world is a will to power...
这个世界拥有丰富的能量
and nothing besides.
此外，你别无所有
Pretty pretentious there.
吉姆，你成为大家注意的焦点了
Not easy to follow. A little incoherent.
我很想弄明白
Dancing bears, Nazism, masturbation.
你这片子里的意思
What's next?
片子里想证明的是怎么样的人物？
- What do you guys think? - A bore, man. l hated it.
同学们，你们怎么看？
lt was better than a Warhol picture!
这当然是一副描写事件的图画
lt was worse!
没有这样的事件存在!
A guy sleeping for seven hours?
一个具有指导性意义的...
There was no political conscience.
领袖人物
- You need your art spoon-fed to you. - Right on!
大家请安静!
Hold it down. Let's ask the filmmaker what he thinks.
安静，我来问问制片人
l quit.
我不上这课了
Awake.
出众的人
Shake dreams from your hair, my pretty child, my sweet one.
从梦中醒来吧，我的宝贝
Choose the day and choose the sign of your day.
选择一天，标上印记
The day's divinity. First thing l see.
这将会成为神圣的一天
Come on out for a walk.
出去散散步吧
lt's a beautiful night.
今晚的夜色很美
A vast, radiant beach...
闪闪发光的海滩
and a cool, jeweled moon.
宝石般的月亮
Couples, naked, race down by its quiet side.
裸露的人们成双成对 在海滩上奔跑
And we laugh like soft, mad children...
我们像孩童般大笑
smug in the woolly, cotton brains of infancy.
小小年纪，自鸣得意
Every time l try to make love to you
每一次我想和你做爱
you run around with your mouth stuck out
你就大叫大喊地乱跑
Choose, they croon, the ancient ones. The time has come again.
远古之物在轻声低吟
Choose now, they croon, beneath the moon...
他们在月光下，在远古的湖畔...
beside an ancient lake.
轻声低吟
Enter again the sweet forest.
再一次进入可爱的森林
Enter the hot dream. Come with us.
跟我一起进入梦想
Everything is broken up...
世间万物...
and dances.
纷纷起舞
l can't believe it's so beautiful.
其美丽让我难以置信
"Now l have come again to the land of the fair, strong and the wise.
如今我又回到了那片土地 空气和人群中
Brothers and sisters o'er the pale forest.
兄弟姐妹们在尽情地玩耍
O, children of night...
孩子们...
who among you will run with the hunt?
在你的四周追逐嬉戏
Now, night arrives with her purple legion.
如今我回到了魂牵梦萦的故乡
Retire now to your tents and dreams.
明天要去我出生的地方
Tomorrow we enter the town of my birth.
那是令我复活的那块土地
l want to be ready."
神秘又美丽
lt's beautiful.
太美了
- Do you like that? - lt's beautiful.
-真的吗？ -太美了
l've never read much poetry before.
我以前没读过多少诗
What's a shaman?
萨满是什么？
He's a medicine man...
是个巫师
of the lndians.
印第安人
He gets into a peyote trance...
他能念让阴魂附身的咒语
and he gets deeper and deeper, and then he has a vision...
很神秘是吧？的确，他能够看透...
and the whole tribe is healed.
过去和未来
All cultures have a version of it.
所有的文化都有其变形
Greeks had theater and gods.
比剧院比上帝还要伟大
The lndians say the first shaman invented sex.
人们往往把这些人...
They called him "The One Who Makes You Crazy."
看作是最疯狂的人
What turns you on?
你喜欢什么？
l don't know.
我不知道
Experience.
体验
Freedom.
自由
Love. Now.
爱和现在
You know, the first time l did acid, l saw God.
吉姆，现在我第一次 感到了上帝的存在
And l saw a friend of mine who was Christ and Judas too.
我看到朋友反目，互相敲诈
Then l realized that...
我并不认为...
that was the secret of everything.
世界上所有事情有什么神秘
We're all one, the universe is one...
地球只有一个，宇宙也只有一个
and that everything is beautiful.
所有一切都是美丽的
l feel most alive...
我常常感到
confronting death...
生命和死亡是紧紧相连的
experiencing pain.
死亡是很美的事情
l think you're most alive by recognizing beauty.
我认为生活是美丽的 这还说得过去
Seeing truth.
死亡
Does death turn you on?
难道
You love death?
你爱死亡吗？
Life hurts a lot more.
我感觉过好多次了
When you die, the pain's over.
没有痛苦的死亡
All the poems have wolves in it.
印第安巫师都说过类似的话
All but one.
将死亡描述为...
The most beautiful one of all.
最美的东西
"She dances in a ring of fire...
她沿着火堆转圈跳舞
and throws off the challenge with a shrug."
显示出一种挑战心理
That's beautiful.
太美了
Who did you write that for?
让我们试试
l wrote it for you.
我爱你
Try acid, Ray.
你想出...
lt's guaranteed.
法子了吗？
Shit, Morrison.
你又来了
My last trip was a real bummer, man.
你净干些没用的事
l never had a bummer on acid.
这话怎么说？
l'm trying naturally high now.
不过我会努力的
Whatever works.
如果你能成为电影策划人
Making movies at MGM yet?
我还会写出不少歌词
l got in to see the head of production.
那我的作品一定不少
He said, "Where's your script?" l said, "l don't need a script.
吉姆，不用剧本...
Godard doesn't use a script. He improvises."
就可以找到镜头前的感觉
The guy says, "Great. Who's Godard?"
太棒了，好家伙，太棒了
l'm off movies, man.
老兄，从你的电影中苏醒过来吧
l went out to the desert. Got lost.
一切都会转瞬即逝
l've been living up on Trick's rooftop.
我从来找不到什么捷径
- Got stuck on a chick. - So what else you doing?
-那还得依靠你 -你干什么？
Writing songs, poems. Stuff like that.
我写歌曲，写诗，就这些
You're writing songs?
你写歌曲？
So let me hear one.
一定相当不错了
l'm shy.
只是尝试
- Sing it to me. - l can't sing.
-你别谦虚了 -随你怎么说
You sing better than Dylan?
我们可以干得比拍电影还要好
Johnny's in the basement
任何事只要有了牢固的基础...
Mixing up the medicine l'm on the pavement
便有好的结局
Thinking about the government
有我的帮助，你会达到事业的顶峰
Let me hear your words.
有什么新词吗？
All right.
好吧
Let's swim to the moon
“让我们向着月亮游泳”
Let's climb through the tide
“让我们顺着潮汐攀登”
Penetrate the evening
“穿透黑夜”
That the city sleeps to hide
“这城市躲在夜幕下”
Let's swim out tonight, love
“让我们今晚出去游泳吧，宝贝”
lt's our turn to try
“是时候试试了”
Park beside the ocean
“把车停在沙滩上”
On our
“开始我们的...”
Moonlight drive
“夜光之旅”
Those are great fucking lyrics, man.
还真不错
- Yeah? - Yeah. You write this?
这是你写的？
You got others in here?
你的脑子里还有其他的歌吗？
A bunch, man. l got a whole concert in my head.
去你的，我也不知道 我的脑子里都装了些什么
l can see it all.
好像净是这些玩意儿
What the hell happened to you in the desert, man?
老兄，碰上你是我命中注定的
- Ecstasy and madness. - Let's get a band together...
灵感还在下一首歌呢
and make a million bucks!
多美的字句!
- l got tons of songs. - Things are about to explode.
你还能写出不少这样的作品
l can feel it in the air. People want to fight or fuck.
吉姆，如今人们都他妈的爱上了杀人
Love or kill. Vietnam is right out there.
在地球的那边，在越南 一切都那么的疯狂
Sides are being chosen.
孩子们不明白真相
Everything's gonna flame. The planet is screaming for change.
都被阿灵顿公墓中 所谓的英雄给迷惑了
We gotta make the myths.
我真想改变这一切
There ought to be great orgies, man.
伙计，你既伟大又坚定
When Dionysus arrived in Greece, he made all the women mad.
这世界充满了见利忘义的小人
Leaving their homes and dancing off into the mountains.
女人们走出家门四处游荡
There should be great, golden copulations in the streets of L.A.
人们知道这其中联系的奥秘吗？ 真像是一帮无赖
We should call ourselves Dionysus.
这事已成定局
l got a name. Doors.
我已经知道该怎么写了
You mean "The Doors ln Your Mind"? The Huxley book?
就叫门 关起门来人们可以回想一切
- Doors of perception. Acid. - That's great.
门是一种感觉，是问题的核心 是问题的本质
The quote's from William Blake.
是的，门是一种感觉
"When the doors of perception are cleansed...
尽管它沉默寡言
things will appear as they truly are."
但它可以洞察一切
Mescaline experiments. Reducing the sugar flow to the brain.
我喜欢它
Come on!
来吧!
You know the day destroys the night
“白天摧毁黑夜”
Night divides the day
“黑夜分割白天”
Try to run
“试着奔跑”
Try to hide
“试着躲藏”
Break on through to the other side
“穿到门的另一边”
What's the matter?
怎么回事？
- lt just doesn't sound right. - l know that, John.
-我觉得这有点不像是首歌 -约翰，你那么认为
Jim, stay in time.
吉姆，是节拍问题
l say we try that bossa nova beat.
我认为是鼓太快了点
l think it's hot.
我认为这歌挺棒的
l think the lyrics are kind of weird.
我想也是节拍的问题
You write one, man.
你们都这么说
We need more songs anyway.
我可唱不出比这更好的了
l thought it was pretty good.
这歌挺好的
Let's go outside.
我们出去一会儿
l came up with something.
谢谢你，萨姆
A minor, then F sharp.
妈妈理解我的忧虑
You know that it would be untrue
“你知道这不是真的”
You know that l would be a liar
“你知道我是个骗子”
lf l was to say to you
“如果非要我说”
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
“宝贝，我们已到达高潮”
Come on, baby, light my fire
“来吧，宝贝，点燃我的爱火”
- G, A, D. - Pretty good. Pretty neat.
-“G，A，D” -这首歌是你写的吧？
Try to set the night on fire
“让这个夜晚充满爱火”
Great, Robby. You got nice changes in there.
很好，罗比，你修改得不错
- Got anymore lyrics? - l got some.
-你们在偷偷的干吗？ -你喜欢吗？
l call it "Light My Fire."
我意识到我现在很喜欢 自 己充满激情的时刻
lf l'm gonna compete with your stuff, it better be about earth, snakes or fire.
这可不是什么奉承话 火焰中的蛇
l like it. Sounds like the Byrds though.
我喜欢这个称呼
But l like it. lt's good.
听起来
A little Latin beat'll do it some justice.
就像是个非凡的人物一样
Maybe put a couple long solos, like Coltrane on "My Favorite Things."
我喜欢它，很不错 我们就这么干下去
Start over, man.
从头开始吧
A minor, B minor. lt's jazz.
你得明白，你得明白
The time to hesitate is through
“不必再犹豫”
- Some kind of intro. - No time to wallow in the mire
-你是音乐的宝库，知道吗？ -“不必再沉溺”
Try now, we can only lose
“放手试试，别怕失败”
And our love becomes a funeral pyre
“让我们的爱变成干柴烈火”
Come on baby, light my fire
“来吧，宝贝，点燃我的爱火”
-是这样吗？ -不，不过我喜欢“来吧，宝贝，点燃我的爱火”
-是这样吗？ -不，不过我喜欢
Try to set the night on fire
“让这个夜晚充满爱火”
- Can you give me-- - Try now, we can only lose
-罗比，你能给我... -“放手试试，别怕失败”
Can you give me five minutes? l got to figure out some kind of intro.
你能给我五个月的时间 让我把这些都弄好吗？那么长
- Let's let him work. You like that? - Yeah, l like Laguna Beach, man.
是的，就这样，我喜欢
Funeral pyre.
焰，火焰
What do you think about when you play?
罗比，你对演出怎么看？
l don't know.
这个，我可拿不准
Fish in my fish tank.
但愿我们这班生手能如鱼得水
- How about that acid tonight, man? - Not for me.
我想应该成功的，你明白这一点
- Not me, either. - Right here at Ray's house.
管他呢，我想让我们去冒一次险
See what kind of trouble we can get into tonight.
我想那一晚肯定会非常有趣 不是吗？
No way. You always get all the chicks.
任人评价吧，演砸了...
l always get the dogs.
有大伙担着
Hey, l got it! Come on!
准备开始
l got it! l got the intro!
我想拿下乐谱
Hang on a second. John, count off in four, man.
练习一下，现在可以开始了
One, two, three.
1，2，3
ls that horny fucker in the black pants here tonight?
穿着黑裤子的那个帅哥今晚在吗？
'6个月后，日落大道" 穿着黑裤子的那个帅哥今晚在吗？穿着黑裤子的那个帅哥今晚在吗？
ls that horny fucker in the black pants here tonight?
穿着黑裤子的那个帅哥今晚在吗？
No l.D.'s, you can't get in.
"6个月后，日落大道" 没有身份证，你不能进去
没有身份证，你不能进去"6个月后，日落大道" 没有身份证，你不能进去
No l.D.'s, you can't get in.
"6个月后，日落大道" 没有身份证，你不能进去
Yeah, we chased our pleasures here
“我们来此追逐快乐”
Dug our treasures there
“寻找宝物”
Can't you still recall The time we tried
“你能否记得，我们努力的日子”
Break on through to the other side
“穿过门的另一边”
Turn around, man. Come on, let them in.
唱吧，吉姆，你听见了吗？
l found an island in your arms
“我在你的臂弯里找到了一个岛屿”
A country in your eyes
“在你的眼睛里找到一个故乡”
Arms that chain us Eyes that lie
“你的手臂锁住我，眼睛在撒谎”
Break on through to the other side
“穿过门的另一边”
All right
好
l'm a big fan! Give it to me!
我是你的歌迷!给我!
Made the scene
“制造大场面”
Week to week
“一周又一周”
Day to day Hour to hour
“一天又一天，一小时又一小时”
The gate is straight Deep and wide
“大门向你们敞开着”
Break on through to the other side
“穿过门的另一边”
All right
好
Hi, Jim. Can l have your autograph?
吉姆，我听过你所有的歌
- l don't know. Where do you want it? - Anywhere you want it.
-真的吗？我不知道 -是真的
Leave it to me. l can take you all the fucking way.
小伙子们，你们唱得真不错
- You blew my mind. - Did you like the music?
-看来前途无量啊 -你喜欢这音乐吗？
l loved it. That's why we're talking.
音乐，我能爱音乐吗？
Some of it's on the dark side. You ought to get some tunes.
那只是我弹的对象而已
Herman's Hermits stuff. Mrs. Brown, you've got a lovely daughter
只要与我合作
That shit goes right to the radio.
你们的身价很快就会大为不同的
l need him here to groove on my boyfriend.
好的 我会把这消息告诉我男朋友的
What about getting us some real equipment?
那我们现在该怎么做呢？
l sign you to a five-year management contract--
我想你们最好还是找个经纪人
You with the joint. Put that out, please.
把它熄灭
- We can smell that upstairs. - l can get you there.
楼上都能闻到味道
Trust me for a while. What do you say?
比尔先生是可以信任的
We'll have a band meeting on it.
我们会开会商量这事的
We do everything unanimously or we don't do it.
要是你们不怀好意的话 我们绝不干
The Musketeers.
我们会很好合作的
l'm touched.
这点你们尽管放心
Let me tell you something. Loyalty don't pay the bills.
最好赶在明天
Think about it and call me tomorrow. Here's my card.
你们就把事情决定了 这是我的名片
Pay attention. You could get rich.
注意，发财的机会到了
- Are you blind? - How old are you?
-别放弃啊 -小伙子，你多大了？
- Twenty-one. - Get lost, will you?
-正是堕入爱河的年龄
l'll make this quick and to the point. lf you repeat it, l'll deny it.
我想我们还是尽快的进入正题吧
Drop those guys.
我们合作怎么样？
Jim's got to start facing the crowd if he's going to be our front man.
吉姆要是不干怎么办？等着瞧吧
He's just getting his confidence.
吉姆他肯定会同意的
- The guy never does what's rehearsed-- - Well, how does it feel?
-你又不是不知道他的脾气 -感觉什么？
lt feels great, but--
我感觉有点担心
Your looks. Your voice. That's what's going to sell records.
你是个讨人喜欢的幸运家伙
We'll make a million bucks a year.
我们会让人人都喜欢上你的
Call me. l'm right.
给我打电话，我会很高兴的
Hey, man, let's go.
我们走吧
Do yourself a favor. Call Larry.
抓住机会
l like a guy who wears his soul on his face.
这就会有很多钱了
Whisky's next, man. l can feel it in my bones.
伙计，这只是开始 我感觉我们要发财了
l still think the lyrics are weird.
是个好家伙
The days are bright
“白天很明亮”
And filled with pain
“充满了痛苦”
Enclose me in your gentle rain
“用你的细雨把我包裹”
The time you ran
“你奔跑起来”
Was too insane
“很疯狂”
We'll meet again
“我们会重逢”
The chicks are really digging you tonight, man.
老兄，想要理解你的歌还真不容易
We still got to deepen, man.
你的歌还真有点深沉啊
- We got to go one more step. - Turn around and face the crowd.
-仅仅一步之遥 -你转过身周围那么多人
lt'll help present it better.
你得去感觉
l got to go to the desert and take that peyote.
你把那些枯燥无味的歌手...
ls that what you're on?
都震住了
Yeah, man. lt's kicking in!
见鬼了，傻瓜!
- Fucking longhair! - He's fucking crazy.
滚开，让我们去快活快活
- Come on. - l'm not doing acid, man.
-去你妈的 -伙计们伙计们
lt's peyote.
伙计们
What's a rock and roll band for?
你们看，咱们这帮捣蛋鬼
Let's plan a murder or start a religion.
咱们四个人组合得不错啊
More, more, more!
我们乐意，伙计们!
l'm into T.M., man. l promised my guru.
我们得去疯狂一回
l'll try it. l'm ready.
找些更多的，更多的女人，更多的妞
Let's go to the desert.
我们去沙漠吧
Let's do the peyote.
我们去佩约特吧
Who's on next?
接下来是谁？
Arthur Lee. He's cool.
亚瑟.李，他很棒
l am the lizard king!
我能为你们做一切!
l can do anything!
我给你们带来了一些
Raise your hands if you understand.
快呀，如果你们听懂了把手举起来
Let's take a poll. How many of you know you're alive?
我说正因为你们热爱生活
Bullshit!
就应该懂得把它抛弃!
You're plastic soldiers in a miniature dirt war.
我喜欢在恰当的时候 走近这肮脏的世界
Come on!
得了!
How many of you people know you're alive?
你们是怎样热爱这现实生活的？
Close your eyes.
考验大家的时候到了
You see the snake.
这是一条像蛇一般...
See the serpent appear?
蜿蜒的道路
His head is ten feet long...
我们成群结队
and five feet wide.
到这里来寻求自身的感受
He has one red eye and one green eye.
这是寻求新鲜自我的地方
That's all right. lt gets better.
一会儿就会好的
Peace.
嗯...
Seven miles long.
有七英里长
Deadly.
它很长
See it. All the history of the world...
不是吗？即使历史在宇宙中的位置
is on its scales.
也是渺小微不足道的
All people. All actions.
人类的一切行为
We're all just little pictures in the scales.
都在生命的蓝图上留下了印记
God, it's big.
它是巨大的
lt's moving.
它是活跃的
Devouring consciousness.
孕育着紊乱可怕的力量
Digesting power.
非常恐怖的能量
Monster of energy.
它是个怪物
lt's a monster.
l'm gonna kiss the snake on the tongue.
轻轻触摸着所有的人
Kiss the serpent.
轻轻触摸着我
But if it senses fear...
这种直觉...
it'll eat us instantly.
使人们感受到...
But if we kiss it without fear...
它的无所不在
it'll take us through the garden.
毫无顾忌地轻轻触摸
Through the gate.
从上帝到国王
To the other side.
到其他方方面面
Ride the snake...
通过这条...
'til the end of time.
时间之蛇
l think l'm fucked up, man.
我感到隐隐作痛，伙计
l'm not thinking right.
我能站起来吗？
Look at your eyes, man. You're death.
我会死的
l'm afraid of my father.
我害怕我的父亲
l can't be what they want me to be.
我担心会发生令人震惊的事
Maybe you should kill your father.
或许他们会杀了你的父亲
l'm in pain, man.
我是个很脆弱的人
l feel the universe functioning perfectly...
我感受到宇宙那无所不在的作用
but l'm still perfectly locked inside myself.
我看到了最完美的东西
lnstead of oneness, l feel isolation.
衣食可以解脱我们的孤独
But you're alive.
你们难道喜欢恐怖吗？
- Feel it. - l'm scared.
我感到害怕
- lt's beautiful. - l'm still scared.
-太美了 -我害怕
Then use us.
没用的
Use our strength. Come on in here.
孩子，过来，你真没用
That's right.
我们现在试试
We're a tribe now. A tribe of warriors.
试试更多的能力
l promise you, l'll be with you to the end of time.
向你保证 我将与你一同走向时间的终点
Nothing will destroy our circle.
我们围在蛇的旁边...
Ride the snake.
不再四处流浪
Come on.
好了，来呀
My wild love went riding
“我狂野的爱正在奔驰”
She rode all the day
“她整天骑着它”
She rode to the devil
“她骑着它奔向恶魔”
Asked him to pay
“让他偿还”
My wild love went riding
“我狂野的爱正在奔驰”
She went to the sea
“她骑着它奔向大海”
She went to the devil
“她骑着它奔向恶魔”
All that's left was we
“只留下我”
l'm lying. l am afraid.
我，我害怕了
Don't go away!
吉姆，别走开!
Come dance with me!
到我这儿来!
Where you going, Jimmy?
你愿意到我这儿来吗？
This is the end
“这是终点了”
Beautiful friend
“亲爱的朋友”
This is the end
“这是终点了”
My only friend, the end
“我唯一的朋友”
Of our elaborate plans
“我们精心计划的终点”
The end
“一切的...”
Of everything that stands
“终点”
The end
No safety or surprise
“无需惊讶”
The end
“终点”
l'll never look
“我绝不会...”
lnto your eyes
“再次...”
Again
看你的双眼
Can you picture what we'll be
“你能描述我们的未来吗？”
So limitless and free
“毫无限制，随心所欲”
Desperately in need
“急切地需要...”
Of some stranger's hand
“陌生人的手”
ln a desperate land
“在绝望之地”
Lost in a Roman
“迷失在罗马”
Wilderness of pain
“无尽的痛苦”
And all the children
"1966年 洛杉矶威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
“所有的孩子...”"1966年 洛杉矶威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
And all the children
"1966年 洛杉矶威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
Are insane
“都疯了”
Waiting for the summer rain
“等待着夏雨”
There's danger on the edge of town
“镇上充满危险”
Ride the king's highway, baby
“在国王的大路上奔驰”
Weird scenes inside the gold mine
“金山里出现神秘场景”
Ride the highway west, baby
“在大路上往西奔驰”
Ride the snake
“骑着蛇”
To the lake
“到湖边”
The ancient lake, baby
“那远古的湖边”
The snake is long
“那蛇很长”
Seven miles
“足有七英里”
Ride the snake
“骑着蛇”
He's old
“它很老”
And his skin is cold
“它的皮很冷”
The west is the best
“西方乃极乐世界”
Get here and we'll do the rest
“到达那里便不必烦恼”
The blue bus
“忧郁的汽车”
ls calling us
“在召唤我们”
Driver, where you taking us
“司机，你要把我们带向何方”
The killer awoke before dawn.
“杀手在黎明前醒来”
He put his boots on.
“他穿上靴子”
He took a face...
“他看了一眼...”
from the ancient gallery...
“远古的画廊”
and he walked on down the hall.
“然后他走向大厅”
He went into the room where his sister lived.
“他走进他妹妹住的房间”
Then he...
“然后”
paid a visit to his brother.
“他看了看他的弟弟”
Then he--
“然后”
He walked on down the hall.
“他继续往大厅走”
And he came to a door.
“他来到一堵门前”
He looked inside.
“他往里看”
"Father." "Yes, son?"
“爸爸”“怎么了，孩子？”
"l want to kill you."
“我要杀了你”
"Mother."
“妈妈”
l want to
“我想要...”
fuck you all night, baby
“整夜地操你”
Come on, baby
“来吧，宝贝”
"Mother, l want to fuck you"?
“妈妈，我想要操你？”
Come on
“来吧”
Fuck, fuck
“操，操”
Turn him off! Turn his fucking amp off!
关掉!把他的音箱关掉!
Fuck me, baby
“操我，宝贝”
Come on, baby
“来吧，宝贝”
- He's insane! - He's a great artist!
-他疯了! -他是个伟大的艺术家!
- We all love it! - Come on
-我们爱你! -“来吧”
All right
“来吧”
Kill
“杀”
Get him out of here!
把他赶出去!
- Get the fuck out of here! - Kill the father.
他妈的，你给我放开
Nobody's gonna fuck their mother on my stage!
去你妈的，你这个狗杂种
- That's what l mean! - You're out of here!
你给我放开，给我放开
Kill your father! Fuck the mother!
去你妈的，放开我
All right!
来吧
Jerry, come on, man!
来吧，来吧
- Art, man! lt's art! - What do you know about art?
-你给我滚出去! -我要唱，我要唱
Take a look at the future, old man!
他妈的，我还要唱
We're things to come!
你听见了吗？
Here's art.
你这个狗杂种
- There's your art! - This is fucking great!
-我还要唱! -好啊，你们这帮混蛋
- We'll never work in this town again. - Quite a night.
行了，这帮混蛋 我们不能再唱这种歌了
l'm Jac Holzman.
你们好，我叫杰克逊
- l own Elektra Records. - ls that asshole gonna pay us?
-我拥有一个唱片公司，是吗？ -我要唱
l think if you can put what you did in there on record...
首先 我认为你们得改变一些演唱方式
we could really have something and make a lot of money.
你们可能还不了解唱片 对成名的作用
Rothchild here was born to be your producer.
你们可以灌一些好唱片 可以赚很多钱
How you doing? Sorry about all this. You guys are--
让理查给你们介绍吧 你们好，小伙子们
Bertolt Brecht. lt's cabaret. lt's rock and roll.
我认为摇滚乐从来就是 疯狂的吼叫扭捏作态
l'm really blown away, guys.
我很熟悉这些东西
l'd like to get you guys into a studio immediately.
要唱得柔和一点 你们打算马上开始吗？
How would you like to come down from there and make a record?
莫里森，快下来，你要休息
Sure. Pretty good. Pretty neat.
当然，为什么不呢，快下来
Bruce, you feel it?
效果不错
lt's bitchin'.
是啊，效果不错
An album of killer music in six days. Six days, baby.
我们还有六天的时间呢
Unreal.
“不真实的”
The time to hesitate is through
“让时间去证明”
No time to wallow in the mire
“而时间显得多么珍贵”
Try now, we can only lose
“现在，我们没有东西可失去”
And our love become a funeral pyre
“我们的爱，变成了坟墓”
Come on, baby, light my fire
“来吧，点燃我的火焰”
Try to set the night on fire
“把夜晚也点燃”
"1967年，旧金山" “把夜晚也点燃”“把夜晚也点燃”
Try to set the night on fire
"1967年，旧金山"“把夜晚也点燃”
"1967年，旧金山"
L.B.J.! L.B.J. !
L.B.J.!
How many kids have you killed today?
“你今天杀了多少人？”
You know that it would be untrue
“你知道，一切都是不真实的”
You know that l would be a liar
“你知道，我是骗你的”
lf l was to say to you
“如果我要跟你说”
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
“女孩，我们要更兴奋”
Come on, baby, light my fire
“来吧，点燃我的火焰”
Try to set the night on fire
“把夜晚也点燃”
All right!
好啊!
- Name? Occupation? - Bill Siddons. l'm the manager.
-姓名？职业？ -我是比尔.西登斯，经纪人
l manage the Doors.
我是大门的经纪人
- Name? Occupation? - Pamela Morrison. Ornament.
-姓名？职业？ -帕姆拉.莫里森，形象设计
Robby Krieger. Guitar player.
罗比.克雷格，我是吉他手
John Densmore. Percussionist.
约翰.丹斯莫尔，鼓手
Twenty-two years old. Far out, man.
23岁
- Name? Occupation? - Raymond Daniel Manzarek.
-姓名？职业？ -雷蒙德.亚历克斯
Born 2-12-39. Musician. Organist.
我是一个作曲家，演奏电子琴
- Name? Occupation? - Jim.
-姓名？职业 -吉姆
1967年，纽约
We're gonna be on TV.
我们要上电视了
Right this way, Mr. Sullivan.
沙利文先生
They're called the Doors...
我会把一切都安排好的
and they've got the number one single in the country right now.
好的，他们的乐队叫大门
"Light Your Fire."
那首“点燃你的火焰”...
Now, they're not your usual group...
目前是全国最热门的歌曲
but l think they're gonna fit in just fine.
“点燃我的爱火”
Everything's gonna be fine.
你是这么说的吗？
The riot continues in Detroit, with 1,400 buildings burned.
是的 现在你可以把一切都控制住了
No wonder "Light My Fire" is number one.
这是我最好的一首歌
So, what's your room number?
你的房间号码是多少？
l'll talk to you later.
我以后会告诉你的
- You have got very serious hair. - Were you pinching her butt?
-这会儿还真严肃 -亲爱的，你这么认为吗？
- What about me? - l won't open that kettle of worms.
我什么呀？我想在这儿照张相
What about you, handsome? What can we do?
你对那些流言蜚语怎么看？
Some of the worst mistakes of my life have been haircuts.
我想有些话会毁了我
Don't wash it. Don't set it. Go away. l like it just the way it is.
你别这样梳，这种发式不适合他
- Be mean. - Boys. Boys.
-好了，我走开 -小伙子们
Meet Mr. Sullivan.
来见见沙利文先生
Fellas, just great.
小伙子们
-l heard your record, "Light That Fire." -"Light Your Fire."
我听过你们的唱片 今晚你们唱的那首...
- Just-- - "Light My Fire."
“火焰”
Fine. Just really, really fine.
“点燃你的火焰” 反正就是火焰，你来说吧
l have one small thing to bring up.
有一点小事要告诉你们
But it's important. The guys at network told us...
事情虽小，却很重要 你们千万得记住
they have a little problem...
有一个小小的问题就是
with the lyric, "Girl, we couldn't get much higher."
当你们和台下进行交流的时候
You can't say "higher"...
可别太出格
on network.
她们要问的话
They asked if you could say, instead...
你们可以说可以唱
"Girl, we can't get much better."
姑娘们，我们会干得更好的
- Can you dig that? - How about...
你们明白吗？
"Girl, you couldn't bite my wire"?
要是说，姑娘 你可别上我的钩，怎么样
l don't think Standards and Practices would--
得了，我认为不要在舞台上 搞那些乱七八糟的玩意儿
Why don't you have a nice, big smile on your face when you get out there?
你们的表演要恰到好处
There's no point in being sullen.
放机灵一点，都得站在突出的位置
- You know what l mean? - We're a sullen group, Ed.
-但别太火爆了，明白了吗？好好演吧 -难道要我们装哑巴？
You boys should know, Mr. Sullivan is considering you for four more shows.
沙利文先生是想让你们的演出 显得更正规一些
- You dig? - We dig.
-明白吗 -我们明白
l'll work it out. Just give me five minutes.
再给我们五分钟时间
- Groovy. - Just give me five.
行了，好吧，但是请注意一点
Have a great show.
祝你们演出成功，就这样
Well?
怎么办？
- Come on. - lt's just a word.
-得了，约翰 -是歌词问题，吉姆
The Stones changed when they played here.
但是演出不能改了
Why don't you change your name to...
对，我们把名称改为...
Sidney or lrving Manzarek?
悉尼艾尔文伙伴乐队怎么样呢？
- lt's just a word. - Hey, man.
可还存在歌词问题，伙计们
My words. l don't care. Let's just jam.
我不介意什么歌词，这取决于吉姆
And now...
现在
direct from Los Angeles, California...
来自加利福尼亚州洛杉矶的...
ladies and gentlemen, here now, the Doors!
摇滚乐队门为大家演唱
You know that it would be untrue
“你知道这不是真的”
We're okay sound wise?
注意了，这是摇滚乐，明白了？
lf l was to say to you
“如果非得我说”
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
“女孩，我们已到达高潮”
He said it!
怎么啦？
He said it on national TV.
他们怎么唱这首歌
- l can't believe that! - Come on baby, light my fire
-我可不同意! -“来吧，宝贝，点燃我的爱火”
What's he doing? What's that?
为什么不能唱？接着唱
Jesus! Get it off! You can see his thing!
-停下，你们赶快给我停下! -他们不是唱得很好吗？
You blew it, you little shit!
你们这样做是违反合同规定的
You'll never play Sullivan again!
你们赶快给我停下来!
Can you just move a step forward?
啊，好了，你能往前挪挪吗？
Come on. l know you love to look at yourself.
过来，我知道你想突出这装饰品
Great.
很好
Let's try something different. Take your shirt off.
让我们试试别的姿势，把衬衫脱了
- You take it off. - Do you need help?
-你来脱 -需要我帮忙
That's good.
很好
The camera is whatever you want it to be.
照相机可以拍出你想要的 任何一种照片
A woman you want to seduce.
吉姆，任何人想拍什么样的都行
A man you want to kill.
对一个想成为社会焦点的男人来说
lt can be anything you want.
相机是再适合不过的了
That's nice.
太好了
That's great!
Do you have any idea what these pictures can do?
太棒了，再来几个动作
One image controls millions of people.
多拍几张
- Where are the Doors? - Right here.
-门在哪里？ -算了吧
Will you forget the Doors?
你得忘了门
You're the one they want.
你就是他们所需要的
You are the Doors. Come on.
来，别动，就这样
That's it. Be ugly.
再来一张
l love that.
坚持一下
Anything you want.
好了，现在到那边去，吉姆
There are no restrictions here.
吉姆，回过头来看我
Look at yourself.
看看你自己
Fall in love with yourself.
爱上自己吧
You're your own audience now.
把大衣脱了
They want you.
他们想得到你
Worship, love you.
崇拜你，我爱你
Adore you.
崇拜你
Jim Morrison.
吉姆.莫里森
The god of rock...
我得到了他
and cock.
Not tonight, Edie. Thank you, not tonight.
把你的工作和生活...
This is the fun part of my job. This is history in the making.
结合得很成功嘛
Would you like to see my imitation of a shrimp?
非常非常成功
Let me put it this way.
有时候我认为
Andy is more than an artist. Andy Warhol is art.
你给美国音乐带来了新的生命
Sometimes l think bright people in America must ask themselves...
你会时不时地感到生活 被音乐融化了
"Does Andy imitate life, or does life imitate Andy?"
你会感到生活被音乐融化了
Jim, this is Tom Baker.
吉姆，这是汤姆.贝克
He's in one of Andy's movies, "l, A Man."
威尼斯电影演员
- And this is Count "Ruspooli." - Ruspoli.
-这位是科特.瑞斯布雷 -瑞斯布雷
He's ltalian, but he lives in Paris.
这是科特，他住在巴黎
He's from a very famous family, 700 years old.
一座有700多年历史的著名城市
Hi, Jim. You are great.
-我叫吉姆 -很高兴认识你
l see you at Ondine's with Hendrix.
我看了你的演出，真是意犹未尽啊
So cool.
太妙了，非常非常美妙
- All right. - Don't you like the way he talks?
难道你们只爱谈这些...
- lt's so cool. - What's your trip?
非常美妙之类的话吗？
My trip? l thought it was yours.
隐私
l caught your gig at The Scene. l thought it was pretty good.
我从来没有见过像这样唱歌的人
l liked it a lot. lt was hot.
我全身的血液都沸腾了
l like your movies, man. You got a great penis.
老兄，我也喜欢看你的电影
We're gonna split. Why don't you come with us?
在威尼斯你真棒
- We're going to get a bite to eat. - No, you can't leave.
吉姆，停一下，我们去和马克谈笔生意 -我怎能离开这里呢？
Where's your will to be weird?
雷，这儿有这么多的新朋友
Look, that's Jim Morrison.
我和他们正聊着呢
l like the Doors.
-生意要谈，吉姆 -我喜欢门
Let's get out of here. These people are wacky.
-嘿，约翰，你认为他怪癖 -怪癖
Come with me. Andy's waiting for you.
我来给你们拍一张
No, not now. Let's do this later.
别这样，你不能照
Do you remember San Francisco?
吉姆，你认为这就是你的目标吗？
- No, not really. - Have another joint.
这个嘛，根本不是
Check it out.
吉姆
This chick here sings with Andy's band, The Velvet Underground.
-吉姆你得当心点 -你说什么？
She says she can drink you under the table.
-那边有个姑娘想认识你 -哦，是吗
Hi, l'm Nico.
你好，我叫妮科尔
lt's so boring tonight.
今晚这儿太没劲了
Some of us are going downtown to a new club.
有人进城去俱乐部了
You want to come?
你想去吗？
Elevate your taste in trolls, man.
伙计，你得赶快决定啊
Vodka?
好
l'll race you.
我去
Your death.
好，我听你指挥
Come on, man. Let's go.
你们怎么了，啊
All right. We're gonna go to a club.
嘿，我们去俱乐部
l think this girl wants to hang out with you.
我真想和你们一块去 你打算在那儿待多久
Don't you want to meet Andy Warhol?
10个钟头吗？
l could do without the guy. He's a freak.
你们怎么不跟着我，咱们走着去啊
Come on. We got a big gig tomorrow.
老兄，告诉你实话 我们很快就会把一切都安排好的
Wait. l thought we were going to be a rock and roll band.
等等我，我们的摇滚乐队是四个人
All right. The four of us.
我们四个人一起去
Come on. This isn't our scene.
一群幻想家
These people are vampires.
Come on, let's make the myths. Remember?
哦，得了，别这样
Let's go.
走吧
Don't leave.
你只会唱歌
Come on, you guys. Not tonight.
快呀，兄弟们
l don't know what'll happen.
今晚我们会知道发生什么了
lt might be death.
我们会死的
lt's not death, man.
伙计，你不会死的
l'll see you tomorrow.
你现在成名人了
Jimmy, this way.
吉姆，上这儿来
Andy's waiting. This way. l'll take you to him.
安迪在等你呢
Hey, daddy.
哦，你好，吉姆
Jimmy, please. Come on.
呵呵
Andy's waiting. Come on.
哦，吉姆，咱们走吧
Hey, man. How you doin'?
从这边走
All right. How you doin', man?
你好吗？
Great.
好极了
Pretty good. Pretty neat.
我是吉姆.莫里斯
There was this big show in Philadelphia.
吉姆这边来，跟我来
Andy.
嘿，大家来认识一下
There were so many people there--
这是吉姆，吉姆.莫里森
This is Jim Morrison of the world-famous Doors musical group.
是那个门乐队的
- Andy Warhol, of course. - Hi. Wow.
你们都喜欢听他的音乐
We really like your music.
我们非常喜欢听你唱的歌
- How you doin', Andy? - Oh, great.
是这样吗，啊？
And there were so many people at the show...
我太喜欢了 演出现场有那么多的观众
the paintings were getting crushed...
外间描述啊
and they had to take them all down.
他一定能造成轰动的
Really, they were kind of...
而且，有很多人都会这么说的
great.
哦，太棒了
Just the walls. You see, Andy was the art.
真是很好
You should do a show with just bare walls.
你们也都见到他本人了 真的很不错哦
We'd really like to use you in one of our movies, Jim.
哦，吉姆
You're really such a beauty.
这类赞赏通常都是留给电影的
Andy says someday everybody will be famous for 15 days.
你的歌，哦，实在是太美了
He'd really be great, wouldn't he?
没人能像这样 15天之内就闻名全国
l mean...
啊，我的意思
lt's the singer, not the song, right?
你真是太伟大了
lt's the astronaut, not the voyage.
有人给了我...
Somebody gave me this telephone.
这个电话
- l think it was Edie, wasn't it? - Yeah, it was Edie.
他说呀...
And she said that...
我能用它
l could talk to God with it...
和上帝交谈
but l don't have anything to say.
我可没那么多话说
Here. This is for you.
那么，就送给，送给你吧
Now you can talk to God.
现在你可以和上帝说话了
Morrison.
莫里森
Come here.
过来
Darling, listen, l pay the bills...
太妙了，太妙了
so l can use any language that l want.
伙计，今晚过得太快活了吧
The guy wants to talk to the bum.
-我会给你打电话的 -我等着你，亲爱的
Check it out, brother.
这个给你
What are your songs about, Mr. Morrison?
莫里森，你的歌里都唱些什么？
Love, death, travel, revolt.
爱情，死亡，旅行，还有其他
We all write the songs.
我们还写一些歌
l'm interested in...
试图表达
chaos, disorder...
灾难混乱的现实
especially activities which seem to have no meaning, like this.
特别是那些 我们都能够观察到的东西
How do you feel about being called "the ultimate Barbie doll"?
你模仿别人的作品时是怎么考虑的
When you say something like that, it's a shortcut to thinking.
是的，我曾经写过一些这类歌 当然会考虑的
And do you think about the dreadful reviews...
对于你的诗歌集封面上的 那些糟糕的垃圾
your new poetry book has gotten?
你是怎么想的？
l guess they didn't understand.
我只能说我不懂你什么意思
- Did you finance its publication? - Have you bothered to read the poetry?
-你的资产公布表真实吗？ -你父亲读过你的诗吗？
You keep denying that nothing good can come out of L.A.
我认为你们这些问题涉及到隐私权
That's a rather provincial attitude.
我想他有权不予回答
- Do you believe in drugs? - l believe in excess.
-莫里森先生，你吸毒吗？ -警察会证明的
ls alcohol considered part of the shaman's wisdom?
那么你是否非常喜欢喝酒？
lt's the American way.
而且常常喝得酩酊大醉？
Every year we spend more money on tobacco and alcohol...
很少有不喝酒的男人
than we do on education.
在一个懂得尊重妇女的国度里 吸烟喝酒当然也是允许的了
- On behalf of the British press-- - What about the future of the Doors?
-莫里斯先生，你们在英国的演出 -你认为你的乐队
- That's just an excuse for free sex. - How do you spend your money?
-请你说得详细点好吗？ -请你明确答复
l believe in a long, prolonged derangement of the senses...
我一直相信在视觉 和听觉的双重范围内...
to attain the unknown.
人们只能感知到离他们较近的东西
Although l live in the subconscious...
然而如今 我越来越感觉到在我的面前...
our pale reason hides the infinite from us.
还存在一些更高更远的领域 我仅仅是想探索这些领域
Are you, by any chance, in a trance now?
莫里森先生 目前你还会出现精神恐怖吗？
Do you hurt?
你是否听说过？
What?
什么？
What hurts you the most?
什么是最低级的？
What do your parents think about what you're doing?
你的父母对你的所作所为 有什么感想？
Actually, l don't remember being born.
实际上我也记不清 这些枯燥无味的事情了
lt must have happened during one of my blackouts.
他们并没有干涉过我的行动
They must have expressed some feeling.
那他们一定表达过自 己的看法
Well, to tell you the truth, they're not living anymore...
哦，我告诉你们 这些都是过去的事了
so l really don't like to talk about that.
对此我不想再多费口舌
Could you tell us how they died?
你能不能告诉我们他们是怎么死的？
lt was a...
那是一场...
horrible car crash...
可怕的车祸
in New Mexico...
在墨西哥
in the '50s.
50年代
My father ran right into a truckload of Navahos.
我父亲的车正撞在印第安人的卡车上
They were...
all over the highway, bleeding.
高速公路上满是鲜血
Their souls, kind of stirring in the breeze...
灵魂随之而去
just leapt into mine.
他离开了我
l'm sorry.
对不起
Mr. Krieger, do you really consider Mr. Morrison a shaman?
克雷格先生 你真的认为莫里森先生有性问题？
Don't worry about it. lt happens to other guys too.
你担心什么，你这家伙
Wanna do some coke?
哦，我要来点可卡因
lt'll loosen you up.
能让你放松
Sure. The new thing.
当然，我要
Wow.
How old is this?
这有多久了？
That's 14th century.
大约是14世纪
- Witchcraft. - lt's a religion, you know.
-干嘛的？ -是印第安人的自然史
Witchcraft.
干嘛呢？
Witches are the protectors of the seasons...
它是季节性的植物
the goddesses of the grain...
上帝认为它是一种谷物
and when crossed...
可是让它杂交的时候...
destroyers.
它失败了
You ever try drinking blood?
你试过喝血吗？
What?
你说什么？
lt works, you know.
喝血
Drink it at the right time of the moon.
你知道，在月光下将它一饮而尽
They used to dance in the forests naked.
紧接着跳舞，像蛇一样的缠绕在一起
l think that's what offended the Puritans...
那是一种防御性的清教徒式的...
and led to the burnings.
炽热的感觉
They were a sexual threat to their male order...
男人们在那性诱惑...
like the Bacchae.
5天之后
Five days a year, for Dionysus...
他们死去了
they used to wander the hills of ancient Greece.
在这之前，他们面对着那些进攻者
The first witches.
展开搏斗
Clans of wild women...
冒险冲向白种女人
looting...
在这一间大屋子里
fucking...
一切
eating animals raw...
都是乱糟糟的
looking for Dionysus...
等待着最佳的死亡状态
to tear him...
扑上去
to pieces!
把他们咬死
Where do you get the blood?
真勇敢，放血吧
Blood is the rose of mysterious union.
为了表明我们坚定的结合
Symbol of potency.
就让血一滴滴的流下去
- Now you. - l can't cut myself.
-现在该你了 -我会大叫的
Don't be such a child. lf l do it, you have to do it.
哦，别那么孩子气，你得割开
You do it.
你来割
Come on, rock god.
来吧
Fuck me. Fuck me good.
快让我满足
What do you want me to do? What can l do, baby?
吉姆，你还想让我怎么样？
- What's the matter? - Will you die for me?
-我这是怎么啦？ -你为我而死吗？
What do you want me to do?
吉姆
Maybe l should see a doctor or something.
你会离开我吗，我爱你
What do you think? Someone from the Freudian philosophy?
冷静点，帕姆，冷静点 你这样的女孩真少见哪
lt happens to other guys too.
我喜欢听你唱歌
You know, that's the irony.
是吗？
Teenage death girls want my dick, not my words.
那些十几岁的妞儿只喜欢我的钱
lt's not so complicated.
她们并不喜欢我的歌
lt's just sex, you know.
别太复杂了
Never wake up in a good mood again.
现在还不是时候
lt's the hours and the pressure.
如果我们落伍了，被人唾弃了
You do everything like it's your last performance.
哦，你说过你会忍耐的
We weren't built to last. You never know.
人们会嘲笑我们
You're setting yourself up, you know. You're setting yourself up.
-你说过，你说过你会忍耐的 -我们都明白
You're a poet, not a rock star.
你现在是歌手，是诗人 是著名的摇滚歌手
You really know what l am?
只有你才知道我真正是什么
- You know what poetry is? - You don't belong on Ed Sullivan.
帕姆，你是我的诗篇
Who am l?
我是什么人？
Where's the feast they promised us?
我是个享乐主义者
Where's the new wine?
我喜欢好酒
Dying on the vine.
我宁愿死在葡萄架下
See, l lied to you.
我爱你
l loved fame.
我爱名声
l do love fame.
我更爱名声
- Why are you doing this to me? - 'Cause you're here.
-你干嘛这样对待我？ -这是在屋里嘛
And that's gonna help?
我不是一个玩物，你听到了没有？
l don't have this problem with anybody else.
-我不是你的玩物 -给我
Suck it, honey. Come on.
-去你的吧 -你去哪儿
- Fuck you. - Where you goin'? Huh?
哦，过来，你过来，我爱你
Where do you think you're going?
-不，你别碰我 -你过来，过来
Love my girl!
你别碰我!
How many guys have you fucked?
快过来
And how many dogs have you fucked?
你这疯子
You're the only one who couldn't make it, you asshole!
你走，你走
You are the only limp dick in the lot!
-走开 -过来
Will you die for me?
-你别碰我 -愿不愿回到我身边？
- Answer me! - Will you die for me?
-我不愿意跟你在一起 愿不愿意回到我身边？
Sure.
我不要跟你在一起
l'd die for anybody.
我要离开你了
Shut up in there! l'm trying to sleep in here!
不
- Will you die for me? - Yes!
-吉姆 -我要跳下去了
l don't believe you!
愿不愿意回到我身边？
- Say it! - Yes. Yes.
我愿意，你上来
l'm just a clown.
-回到我身边 -我爱你，吉姆
Am l a clown?
-哦，我爱你，吉姆 -愿不愿意回到我身边
l need a home...
对不起
a place to hide.
我爱你
l'm sorry.
对不起
We're gonna fuck death away. Come on.
我爱你
Let's fuck death away. Come on, baby. All right.
-我爱你，吉姆 来吧，让我们，再一次吧
An ancient lunatic reigns in the trees of the night.
今天晚上他们又给我们 带来了精彩的节目
1968年，纽黑文
We've got a serious problem here.
哦，他的歌声给我们 留下了遐想的余地
The fire marshal won't let this concert go on...
请大家严肃一点，严肃一点
unless you clear the aisles and go back to your seats.
演出暂停
Unless you clear these aisles, there is no show.
让乐队休息一下
The sound of the crowd.
休息一下
l don't even like rock groups. They're sleazy.
哦，这里太吵了，上这儿来吧
- You like that, huh? - Like Nuremberg.
-哦，吉姆，你带我到哪儿？ -来吧，这儿很隐蔽
- Like that? - We're Germans.
-你喜欢这儿？ -不会有人来的
- Beg. - l'm begging.
-哦这儿很隐蔽 -没事，来吧，来吧
You wanna fuck me?
你想让我出洋相吗，该死的
Don't ever fuckin' lie to me again.
-是该死的 -混帐家伙
- About what? - Why did you say your father was dead?
我已经筋疲力尽了
He is dead. Both of them. Totally.
这地方很大，没人会来
lf he's so dead, who answered the phone when l called?
我一喊人就会来的
What?
你说什么？
You didn't really think you were getting away with that, did you?
你想干什么就干什么
Your father's an admiral in the Navy...
还想对我随心所欲，是吗？
who was at the Gulf of Tonkin when the Vietnam War broke out.
你是不是还考虑给我钱
Wow.
就像你和女孩子 谈论越南一样的轻松简单
Your dad's deputy chief of operations.
那是你的代理人专有的权利
Just don't ever lie to me again.
可是你别再想找到我
What?
-哦，天哪 -怎么啦？
You shouldn't have done that.
我们不应该那样
Like it's so hard to trace your school records?
哦，我的财运一直很糟
You went to University of Florida, Albuquerque, New Mexico...
可是你却不同 你进过佛罗里达大学
Arlington, Virginia...
到过哈佛，墨西哥，阿林顿...
Washington, D.C.
维吉尼亚，还去过华盛顿
You have a brother and a sister.
哦，你有兄弟姐妹
"Seven Miles Long," baby. lt's all in "The End."
或许，你离他们只有七英里的距离
l'm sorry.
对不起
What did he do?
你想干嘛？
Did he love you?
你爱你自 己
How much?
有多少？
Your mama?
就这么一点
Hatred's a very underestimated emotion.
他感到既无助又无望
Doesn't matter anymore, does it?
还有什么不满足的吗？
Do you hear them out there? Are you listening to them?
他就是一座山，听听那些观众的 叫喊声吧，你现在意识不到吗？
lt's you they want now.
他们并不仅仅对门那样狂热
lt's not the Doors.
好了
lt's not your mother or your father's child.
你这个父母的...
lt's you.
乖孩子
They don't want me. They want my death.
他们想得到我都快发疯了
Ripped to pieces.
就差没把我撕碎了
Patricia, just hold me.
真令人感到...
What you doin' there?
你们在干嘛？
- Nothin'. - Okay, out.
-没干嘛 -过来，跟我走
No one's allowed backstage.
我们出去说
- Don't you know who this is? - lt's cool. l'm with the band.
-怎么啦？ -别发火，我是乐队的
Let's go. Come on.
过来，嘿
- Cool it, pig. - Fuckin' hippie!
-跟我走 -你他妈的狗杂种!
Motherfucker!
臭小子!
They got Jim!
来人啊!
What's happening?
快去看看是怎么回事
What the fuck is going on here?
干什么你，去他妈的警察
l'm blind!
去他妈的臭警察!
- He's under arrest. - Don't shut your eyes, Jim!
-怎么回事？ -这小子不听话!
We gotta get you out.
帕特
Leave him alone.
你让他一个人待着
- He doesn't need more shit in his life. - What do you know what he needs?
-他可不需要你的胡说八道 -你根本不知道他需要什么!
Fuck!
他妈的!
All right
“好了”
Okay
“很好”
All right
“好了”
l am
“我是你的...”
Your back door man
“后门骑士”
"Light My Fire!"
唱“点燃我的爱火!”
Men don't know
“男人不懂得”
Little girls understand
“小姑娘明白”
Fire! "Light My Fire!"
唱“点燃我的爱火!”
Well, all your people
“所有这些人”
Tryin' to sleep
“想要入睡的”
l'm out there makin'
“我来帮你们达成”
Midnight creep
“用我的午夜梦境”
Back door man
“后门骑士”
Men don't know
“男人不懂得”
Little girls
“小姑娘”
Understand
“明白”
All right, yeah
“好了”
Come on
“来吧”
Persian night, babe
“波斯的夜晚，宝贝”
See that light, babe
“望着那光芒”
Save us
“拯救我们吧”
Jesus
“耶稣”
Save us
“拯救我们吧”
l want to tell you about something that happened a few minutes ago...
姑娘们 我想告诉你们几分钟之前...
right here in New Haven.
发生的一件事
This is New Haven, isn't it? New Haven, Connecticut?
我在这纽黑文碰到一件事
United States of America?
在美利坚合众国的纽黑文
ls the West really the best...
嘿，往下说呀
or are you just stoned on weed?
说出来给我们听听啊
Come on! Sing "Light My Fire."
快说吧，说呀，说吧
l was with this girl backstage.
我和在那边台上的一个姑娘
We wanted some privacy...
我们有些私事要谈
so we went into this shower stall.
可就在谈兴正浓的时候被打断了
We weren't doing anything. We were just talking.
当时我们没做别的 只是谈谈话而已
All of the sudden this--
可是有一个...
this little man came in...
卑鄙下流...
with a little blue hat and a little blue suit.
脸色铁青的小人闯了进来
He said, "What you doin' in there?"
他说，“你们在那儿干嘛？”
l said, "Nothing."
我说没干嘛
And he said...
他说...
"Well, you'd better get out of there or--"
“你得跟我过去”
"Or what?" l said.
然后
And he started pushin' me.
然后他开始推我
So l started pushin' back!
你们说我该怎么办
He didn't like that.
我能和他搏斗吗？
Then he reached behind and pulled out a can of Mace...
他向我的眼睛里面喷东西
and sprayed it right in my eyes.
是他妈的从口袋里掏出来的
Fuckin' blinded me!
我一下就什么也看不见了!
Why?
这是为什么？
All because l was alone in a room with a girl...
因为他是警察
doing what he'd like to be doing if he could only get it up without a gun.
就可以对我们这些 手无寸铁的人想干嘛就干嘛
All right!
诸位!
ln the United States of America, man!
在美利坚合众国
Land of the free, home of the brave!
自由之土，美好之乡 !
ln God we trust!
我们相信上帝!
Say your thing, man.
好了好了，大家安静些，你来说说
Mr. Morrison, you've gone too far.
得了吧，莫里森先生
The show's over.
你的话太离谱了
You've violated state obscenity laws.
今天的演出到此为止
- You're under arrest! - There you go!
-可你得跟我们走! -啊，谢谢!
Out of the way!
让开!
Get out of the way!
Back! Keep 'em back!
拦住他们!
Get your hands off me, you slaves.
放开我
This isn't happening to me, man. lt's happening to you.
你们凭什么抓我.你们凭什么抓我
Let's just say l was testing the bounds of reality.
在一些人的检验标准之下
That's all. l was curious.
他看起来稀奇古怪
l always preferred to be hated...
始终成为舆论的矛头指向
like Erich von Stroheim in the movies.
成为警察的目标
The man you love to hate.
那些传统的卫道士们
lt's meant to be ironic...
总在四周徘徊
like courage wants to laugh.
难免令人精神恍惚
Essentially, a stupid situation.
愚昧的环境
l go out on the stage and howl for people.
那些疯狂的观众
ln me they see exactly what they wanna see.
从我身上发现了他们真正的需要
Some say "lizard king," whatever that means.
有些人对我说上帝与你同在
Or some black-clad leather demon...
乌云迟早会散去的
whatever that means.
事实上...
But really, l think of myself...
我认为自己是一个...
as a sensitive, intelligent human being...
对这一切毫无知觉的聪明人
but with the soul of a clown that always forces me to blow it...
任凭外界铿锵有力的怒吼
at the most crucial moments.
将自己与他人隔绝
l'm a fake hero.
公平交易
A joke that God's played on me.
上帝会惩罚他们的
Good morning.
唉，波尔，你好
Pour me my breakfast, Dolores.
操你妈，什么事呢？
What's the matter with Jimbo? Can't handle it, eh?
给我们讲一讲吧
He's pussy-whipped.
伙计，他得和他们斗智了
Hey, Jim, eat this, man. We got one last place to go.
他干得真棒
Ray's getting married this morning. Remember?
太妙了
"Alive, she cried."
记住那句舆论
Can't eat that. lt'll make me sick.
去他的舆论
Give me a Dos Equis, will you, Dolores.
啊，能和我们说说吗？
- And a Ramos fizz. - What happened to you last night?
你是指那件使我解脱的著名事件吗？
"1968年，旧金山"
You bet me $1,000 you were gonna walk on the ledge of the 9000 building.
"1968年，旧金山" 你是指那件使我解脱的著名事件吗？"1968年，旧金山"
-去你的 -你口气倒轻松听说至少有上千份起诉书"1968年，旧金山" 你是指那件使我解脱的著名事件吗？
-去你的 -你口气倒轻松听说至少有上千份起诉书
Let's go right now.
我现在就离开这儿
Complaining about going home to your sanctuary.
你小子这出戏
We were gonna make a movie.
演得不错啊
You bet me 1,000 bucks, man.
老兄，你的阻力不小啊
- Give him a double. - A triple.
-哎，来两杯 -来三杯
lmagine me and Morrison in a movie together.
请看莫里森主演的电影
Two powerful, two lrish...
嘿，多么有力，多么愤怒
two-fisted fuckin' drinkin' guys in the same movie together.
多么有激情，充满了反抗精神
l'll direct it.
再加上一个酗酒的家伙
lf Dennis Hopper can do it, l can.
-胆小鬼 -我也会这么做的
We'll all three direct it. A real road movie in black and white.
还是让我们来演一回巡回电影吧
We'll call it Zero.
比黑白片强多了
- What the fuck? - Fuck you, Morrison!
Get outta here!
滚出去，别在我这儿闹了
Fuckin' jack-off!
滚
Keep the drink.
给我钱，把钱付给我
lt's only another 95,000...
你对我说过，我们有了不少的钱
but l could get the best clothes from lndia, from Morocco, Jim.
啊，现在我们可以去印度，摩洛哥
Clothes you couldn't get anywhere else.
德国，葡萄牙，去任何地方旅行了
Then we could get the richest people to come-- Miles Davis...
如今我们成了最富有的人
Sonny and Cher, the Stones.
像玛尔.戴维斯 沙林.谢尔，斯通一样了
lt could be the best boutique on La Cienega, Jim.
可你还是老样子 我喜欢第一流的东西
Why don't we have a car?
哎，吉姆，再给我买辆车怎么样？
- We lost it. - Yeah, but...
你的车丢了
where's the gravy train?
对，我就是想换一辆新的
What's the matter with you? What are you on?
我要喝点酒 -哦，你怎么了？
You said you wouldn't drink today.
你想怎么样？ 你不是说过今天不喝酒了吗？
No, Ma, l ain't drinkin'.
我没说不喝
You promised you wouldn't drink anymore. You're not gonna drink, are you?
哦，你答应过不再喝的，吉姆
No, Ma, l ain't.
你不会再喝酒了，是吗？
And you're gonna change those stinky leathers you've worn for three weeks.
l don't know about that.
我不知道
What are you on?
那你想干什么
lt's just some low-grade acid. lt's not heavy.
哦，时间都过去了 我可没这么大耐心
Oh, Jim!
哦，吉姆!
Oh, God! l cooked!
哦，我不能再这样下去了
- l cooked the duck! - lt's okay.
我还指望什么
People are coming, you know.
这点希望对我来说已经 是微不足道的了
Ray and Dorothy think that we're flaky enough.
我还在等待，还会有什么结果
You said we'd wait until after, and now you're gonna peak before me.
你只想找机会跟我吵架
No, it's cool. We'll trip, and then we'll eat our feast.
哦，不，不，平静一下 别让野餐不欢而散好吗
Yeah, sure. No!
当然，不，不
You know, l think it's a good thing about Ray and Dorothy.
你，你觉得我们进屋以后坐下来
l do.
有个出色的小家伙围在你的周围-
Women are such noble creatures.
在你死去继承你的姓氏和家产怎么样
They carry on your name with dignity after you die.
我认为这是件好事
Are you saying you want to marry me, Jim Morrison?
吉姆.莫里森，你想和我结婚？
l think women have a comic approach to life. How can they not?
我认为女人们都有些基本的相似之处
They spend their lives with that big dick seeking entry.
但如果没有这些特征的话 男人怎么生存呢？
Come on, Mom.
来吧
l want to look inside, like a spy.
我想看看你的心，像个间谍
l'm a spy
“我是个间谍”
ln the house of love
“住在爱屋中”
l know the dream
That you're dreamin' of
“你做着的梦”
l know the word
“我知道”
That you long to hear
“你渴望听的话”
l know your deepest
“我知道”
Secret fear
“你深藏的恐惧”
l know
“我知道”
Everything
“一切”
l love it when you sing to me.
你看到了不少东西
That's 'cause...
因为...
l'm the poet and you're my muse.
你是我的缪斯，我灵感的源泉
"Lions in the street, roaming.
酷热中的狗
Dogs in heat, rabid, foaming.
列队在街上漫步
A beast, caged in the heart of the city, rotting...
我发现了，发现了兔子
in the summer ground.
笼里收获颇丰
He fled the town...
帐篷边上
left the chaos and disorder back there--u
参差不齐的灌木丛中
Hey, everybody. Here's the nuptial couple.
多好的东西呀，啊.大家过来
What am l gonna do about all these papers?
这里总是乱糟糟的
- Get a drink. - Jim.
-来喝点吧 -吉姆
You really need somebody to organize all this stuff.
吉姆，你的确需要个人 整理你这些乱糟糟的东西
Your handwriting is just like a little kid.
你看这儿简直就像个小孩弄的
Look at this. l wonder if William Blake was ever this disorganized.
你怎么啦，没听见我在叫你吗？
- You're trying too hard. - l'm gonna be your editor now.
-我会把一切都弄好的 -不，我不是这个意思
l'm gonna organize all this stuff and take out all the "fuck" words.
我是说，别把东西到处乱放 别把它们搞得一团糟，你知道吗？
- Honey, you're trying too hard. - No, l'm not.
-好吧，我来收拾 -不，不，我不要
There's some great poetry here, some wonderful ideas.
你看来像个伟大的诗人 还有这么多奇妙的想法
Come on in!
嘿，谁在里面!
- Hey, Jimbo! - Hey, man.
嘿，嘿，你们好啊!
Hi, baby. How's it goin'?
你好，吉姆，嗨，你好
- Yo, Ray. - Hey, Dog, how you doin'?
-你好，吉姆 -保罗在哪儿啊
- Get some drinks over there. - What am l supposed to do?
-他在那边 -他们到这儿来干什么？
Who am l supposed to be around all these people?
哦，这儿给他们搞得乱糟糟的
Darling Pamela.
我真不喜欢他们
l brought you something.
我给你带来一些礼物
You're my girl, that's who.
哦，小姐姑娘，别这样
l'm not your girl.
哦，我根本就没哭
l know you fuck everything that touches you.
你别瞎说了，我根本就没哭，你走吧
- Don't give me that shit. - Come on.
-我不替你收拾这些东西了，真是的 -哦，来呀
l love my girl! Listen, everybody!
嗨，我的姑娘.嘿，各位都听着，听着
Pam and l--
现在，现在帕姆要和我...
She's lookin' good.
跟大家庆祝一下
And to celebrate--
是的，庆祝一下
- Hey, Patricia. - Hi, Jim.
-帕特丽西娅 -你好，吉姆
Pam, have you met--
帕姆，你们以前不认识吧
Do you know--
你是否...
She wrote this great review of my poetry book.
读过她写的那篇关于 评论我诗歌集的文章呢
- Let's go eat that turkey. - Pam, let's set those plates.
-吉姆过来一下好吗？ -好的
Are you Patricia Kennealy?
帕特里西娅，你就是帕特里西娅
You must be Pamela.
你就是帕姆啦
You actually put your dick in this woman?
吉姆，你常和这个女人在一起，是吗？
Well...
哦...
sometimes, yeah.
有时是吧
Well, l understand. l really do.
哦，我明白了
But don't ever expect that Jim's gonna love you or take care of you...
可你并没有真正地期望吉姆.莫里森 会爱上你，或者对你表示好感
because you're one of a hundred.
因为你有上百个候选人
- You don't know when to stop. - Look who's talking.
-得了得了，你别再说了，好吗？ -我有说话的权利
Jim can make up his own mind about who he loves and who he doesn't.
我很愿意吉姆另寻新欢地爱上我 就是排到第几百个又怎么样
Don't kid yourself, sweetheart.
你只能做做他的情妇
He's crazy, but not that crazy. He loves me.
他是昏了头，可他不浑.他爱我
Let's go check those sweet potatoes.
哦
- There they go again. - Chuck!
弗洛里，弗洛里
Gonna be another one of those dinners? You're gonna have to stop this.
-哦，好，我们到那边去吧 -哦，走吧
l'm glad you made it. Jim, Robbie, meet Chuck Vincent.
-帕姆拉，我们到那边待一会儿 -好呢
l just have one more thing to say to you, Jim Morrison.
-嘿，伙计，你好啊，好久没见了 -吉姆.莫里斯我还有一件事
You have ruined another Thanksgiving.
愿这个感恩节使你终生难忘
Bastard! You killed my duck!
滚开，你这骗子!不要脸的 你给我滚!
You ruined my duck!
-你们给我滚! -帕姆拉，帕姆拉 你别生气，别生气!
What did you do to her?
你们走
lt's all right. We're working it out.
哎，你走开，走开 这儿没你什么事，让我来
We'll work it out.
艾迪，你躲开
lt's okay.
帕姆拉你别生气了，别生气了好吗？
Fuck you!
哦，帕姆拉，帕姆拉，你要杀了我吗？
You want to know what murder is?
-让开 -你想杀了我，是吗？
You want a little death?
你想杀了我是吗？
Well, come on.
杀到我了
You want a little death?
来吧，来吧，来吧
Then kill me. Go on, kill me. Come on.
好，你就是想杀了我，是吗？
Kill me. Go on!
好吧，杀吧，杀吧
Come on, give me some death!
杀了我，杀了我
You killed my duck.
你伤了我的心
And l'm still killing your fucking duck.
你弄死了我的鸭子
There! Murder! Death!
去你妈的鸭子!在哪儿？在哪儿？
Duck! Dead!
好，在这儿
Dead! Fucking dead!
我踩死它，我踩死它!
There! The duck is dead!
鸭子，鸭子，好，让它去死
- That's the incredible truth! - Stop this shit! Get sane!
-什么他妈的鸭子，她鸭子死了 -吉姆，住手，你到底要干什么!
Don't ever tell me what to do!
你让人看笑话吗，吉姆
- Yeah, fuck off, Ray. - Fuck off, Ray.
该死的混账
This party's gettin' low-rent.
太可怕了
Let's split.
哦，太遗憾了
Looks like we're not gonna eat.
走吧，走吧，这人怎么会这样
Shit.
妈的
Fuck it. Let's eat this thing.
狗娘养的.还是我来照顾它
What happened to us, Daddy, huh?
我们都干了些什么，吉姆
There was some beautiful poetry, you know.
啊，你不会恨我吧 吉姆，你犯了一个美丽的错误
Hold on, honey.
哦，好了
There was some beautiful poetry, Daddy.
-都过去了 -哦，吉姆
Action!
Your mother's here with your brother.
吉姆
l don't want to see 'em, okay?
请问给我们带来了什么新歌？
- What do you want me to do with 'em? - You hear me?
过一会儿你们就会知道的
They're waiting!
你能不能现在就向我们透露一下？
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们，先生们...
from Los Angeles, California...
下面将要出场的是 吉姆.莫里森的乐队...
the Doors!
门!
Pretty good. Pretty neat.
Not to touch the earth
“别接触土地”
Not to see the sun
“别望着太阳”
Nothing left to do but run, run, run
“除了跑没什么可做的”
Let's run
“跑吧”
House upon the hill
“立马山峰”
Moon is lying still
“月亮高挂”
Shadows of the trees
“树影婆娑”
Witnessing the wild breeze
“清风拂面”
Come on, baby, run with me
“宝贝跟我一起跑”
Come on, honey.
哦，我亲爱的
l been so lonely. l miss my girl.
好久没有和你在一起了
l didn't realize you were entertaining.
嘿，你们知道你们在干嘛吗
l hope you are cool about this.
你好，吉姆 我希望你好好面对这件事情
Don't forget your smack on the way out.
你忘了你说过的话吗？
The mansion is warm
“山顶的大厦”
At the top of the hill
“舒适温暖”
Rich are the rooms and the comforts there
“富人在那里寻欢作乐”
Red are the arms
“连椅子...”
Of luxuriant chairs
“都是红木的”
And you won't know a thing 'til you get inside here
“进去了才能体会”
Yeah? Looking for a place to hide, or to die?
这一次是我唯一的选择了
Just doing my thing, like you said.
我那著名的词句
- What? - You're hurting me.
哦，你弄疼我了，吉姆
Are you in pain?
你背着我干这种事...
Let me introduce you to my friend pain.
你还会说痛吗？
Fuck you.
去你的
Oh, sanctuary. Looking for a place to hide?
哦，谢谢你，我的朋友
- l'll give you a place to hide. - From you, you pig.
去寻找你的好时光吧，看你怎么办
Forever.
-你打算把我关多久 -永远
Hey, honey, this is the best part of the trip.
你这臭娘儿们，你说不说实话
Sanctuary.
不
Come on, baby. Come on, honey.
好，谢谢你，宝贝，来呀，宝贝，来呀
Almost home.
快说吧，宝贝，你快说
We're almost home, baby.
-吉姆，不! -宝贝，出来吧
Help!
救命!
- lt's blinding me. - Help! l'm blind!
-我看不见了 -救命!我看不见了!
That's better.
好点了
Ride 'em, cowboy!
上吧!
- Look out. - What?
-吉姆 -什么？
- There's a cop. Slow down. - Where?
-看那儿 -哪儿？
Right there in front! Look!
那儿失火了，那边就是那儿
Dead president's corpse in the driver's car
“总统的尸体在车长车厢里”
The engine runs on glue and tar
“车头在柏油上行驶”
Come on along Not goin' very far
“不用前进多远”
To the East to meet the czar, yeah
“就到东方见沙皇了”
By a right line, the running line, the crooked and the straight...
“沿着直线跑吧...”
l summon you up.
我意志坚如磐石
By wood and stone, wind and fire, land and water, l bring you in.
在烈火中淬炼，在寒风中磨练 我把你们召集在一起
We worship the ancient forces of nature.
希望借助古老祖先的自然之力
The Great Mother, the Triple Goddess...
希望你们共同追寻着这种力量
and the Horned One, god of the hunt.
在混乱的世界中
Death does not part...
共同追寻
only lack of love.
至此永不分开
The goddess holds the vow forever.
直到爱的尽头
Run with me
“跟我跑吧”
Let's run
“跑吧”
The outlaws live by the side of the lake
“歹徒住在湖边”
The minister's daughter's in love with a snake
“部长的女儿爱上了蛇”
Who lives in a well by the side of the road
“蛇住在路边的一口井里”
Wake up, girl We're almost home, yeah
We could see the gates by morning
“到早晨，我们就能看见家门了”
We should be inside by evening
“晚上我们应该能进去了”
Sun, sun, sun
“太阳，太阳，太阳”
Moon, moon, moon
“月亮，月亮，月亮”
l will gain you
“我会得到你”
Soon
“就快了”
l am the lizard king.
我的行动坚定有力
l can do anything.
我想得到一切
Come on, come on, come on Come on now, touch me, babe
“来吧，来吧，抚摸我吧，宝贝”
Can't you see that l am not afraid
“我并不害怕”
What was that promise that you made
“这是你的诺言”
Why won't you tell me what she said
“你为何不告诉我她的话”
Fuckin' Neanderthal prima donna. Too drunk to fuckin' sing.
什么玩意儿，他的节奏老是不稳
l'm gonna love you
“我要爱你”
'Til the heavens stop the rain
“直到天不再下雨”
l'm gonna love you
“我要爱你”
'Til the stars fall from the sky
“直到星星坠落”
You and l
“你和我”
Cut. Cut.
嘿，停一下
Terrific take, Jim. We just had a technical problem in here.
嘿，吉姆，我看还是存在熟练的问题
What's his fuckin' problem, man?
到底什么问题？
- Paul, babe. - Yeah, right here, babe.
-我累坏了 -马上就可以结束了
Suck a fart out of my asshole...
那么你又何必老挑我的刺
you slave-driving fascist--
既然这样我也没有别的办法
- l hear the booze, the smoke. - Sixty-seven takes?
我可碰到了一帮背地里捣鬼的小人
- l don't hear your voice or the song. - Because it's stale!
-什么话，吉姆？ 不我就让你停下来一会儿吗？算了吧
- "Stale"? - l wanna do my thing!
我想干我自己干的事
We'll do 167 takes until it sounds like music.
随便你，你究竟要怎么样？
Let's do something else. You're all a bunch of fuckin' slaves.
那么多的主力 你他妈的想让我成为你的奴隶呀
Let's do--
快快...
Come on, come on, come on.
我们接着来，让他见鬼去吧
Rock is dead.
来呀，来呀，来呀
Everybody come out here. We'll do a sing-along.
我们大家一起来唱
O come, all ye faithful
“来吧，忠诚的信徒”
- Get this circus outta here. - lt's too self-conscious.
哦，来吧，今晚你们觉得怎么样？
Billy, get 'em out! You, you, you! Let's go!
嘿，别这样，别再唱下去了
You deaf? Beat it! Let's go!
嘿，简直太放肆了
See you later.
再见
What are you doing, Jim?
你究竟想怎么样？
l'm sitting in that fuckin' booth for months.
吉姆，在录音棚里一待就是几个月
l look out of the glass, l see Jim, l hear Jim...
我们合作得一直很好 我两眼紧盯着玻璃
but l miss him.
我看着吉姆，我沉溺于吉姆的歌声
And he's standing right in front of me. How do you explain that?
你要知道，我觉得失落了一些东西
Don't make me go through this whole shit again...
每次他总是站在原地一动不动
watching Janis dive to the bottom of a bottle of Southern Comfort.
我不在乎，伙计
l won't go through it again.
或许你不打算再干了
Why are you fucking this up?
可这给我们大家的打击真的很大
l love you, man. You're my own flesh and blood.
这意外发生的事件让我们彼此翻脸 这也太没有价值了
Catchy tune.
我明白了
You sold it to a commercial?
这歌是卖给广告节目的？
- How much? - Seventy-five thousand.
-多少钱？ -75000美元
We couldn't reach you. We figured--
美国的富翁都会对这个数目动心的
- What is this shit, Ray? - lt's not a big deal, man.
-讨厌 -伙计，这是一个很不错的买卖
The song has already been commercialized.
歌曲早就商业化了
Feliciano's already sold two million copies.
就像畅销书那样
Robbie thought it was a good idea. So did John.
罗比认为这是一个好主意
So did l.
约翰和我也这么认为
Robbie?
罗比？
Where were you? You should've been here.
我们只是担心你另有想法
Do you know what you're saying to millions of people?
尽管你们对几百万听众说
The Doors-- all for one, one for all-- not real.
门依赖你们大家，取决于你们大家 可这都不是真的
lt's not about money...
你们没有谈到钱
or records or success...
你们明白
or these...
如何利用唱片
desires that you have.
利用成功和渴望去赚取利润
lt's about...
你们...
using the music to break through.
你们明白用音乐为自 己架桥铺路
Wasn't it, Ray?
不是吗？
l don't know.
可你们也得明白
We lost something here, man.
你们也失去了不少东西
l don't think so, Jim.
吉姆，我不这么认为
There's just a bigger picture, that's all.
只是一些好机会，仅此而已
Yeah?
是吗？
ln your fucking face!
去你妈的好机会
Jesus Fuckin' Christ!
哦，吉姆
What the fuck is goin' on, man?
你疯了吗？
Just kidding.
开个玩笑
Oh, hi, honey.
你们才是最重要的
We were just watching a little TV.
开始看电视吧
l wanted you to find us, Jim. lt meant nothing.
吉姆，你也得考虑考虑我的心情
You don't have to torture me.
你别再折磨我了，别这样
Just let me make it up to you.
我甘愿为你当牛做马
l love you.
我爱你
lt's gonna be all right.
我很快就会好的
You're the one.
你是我的唯一
- Really? - You're my girl.
-是的 -你是我的姑娘
So vulnerable about everything, it makes me sad.
我们以前所说的那些话就让它过去吧
All right, let's keep that money machine rolling.
好了，让我们继续赚钱吧
Can you find me
“ 可以给我找一个”
Soft asylum
“温暖的庇护所吗？”
l can't make it
“我无法...”
Anymore
“支持下去了”
The man is
“那个男人”
At the door
“就在门边”
This is the trip, the best part...
这是我最最...
l really like.
喜欢的部分
Yeah, l'm proud to be a part of this number!
我很荣幸成为其中一分子!
Successful hills are here to stay
“我在成功的顶峰”
Everything must be this way
“一切走上正轨”
All our lives we sweat and save
“生活安逸甜蜜”
Buildin' for a shallow grave
“坟墓上的建筑”
The soft parade has now begun
“游行开始了”
Cobra on my left
“我左青龙”
Leopard on my right, yeah
“右白虎”
Come on
来吧
And it's getting harder
“越来越困难”
Callin' on the dogs
“召集众狗”
When all else fails
“如果再失败”
We can whip the horses' eyes
“我们就合上马的眼睛”
And make them sleep
“让它们睡觉去”
And cry
“然后哭泣”
l love you.
我爱你
Hate your next-door neighbor
“憎恨隔壁邻居”
But don't forget to say grace and
“但别忘了饭前祷告”
Tell me over and over
“一遍遍告诉我”
And over and over again, my friend
“一遍又一遍”
You don't believe
“你不相信”
We're on the eve of destruction
"1969年，迈阿密" “你不相信”
"1969年，迈阿密""1969年，迈阿密" “你不相信”
We're on the eve of destruction
“我们正处在世界末日前夕”"1969年，迈阿密" “你不相信”
“我们正处在世界末日前夕”
A hot night in Miami, March '69.
这里是迈阿密，3月116日晚上
Every space in the auditorium is consumed.
大家可以看到此时全场已座无虚席
Unfortunately, The Doors have long since sold out. They've become an act.
观众情绪十分高涨
Morrison falls off the stage at least every other performance.
轰动一时的摇滚乐队门将在这里演出
"The Soft Parade" album only confirms the plasticity of their approach.
音乐场面一定很壮观，莫里森的歌曲 无疑又将在本地掀起一股热潮
Songs like "Touch Me" and "Tell All the People"...
今晚他们给我们带来的歌曲有 “抚摸我”，“告诉所有人”...
are not the Doors we once knew.
以及大家十分熟悉的歌曲
So the question is: why am l here?
因此我会问为什么这样一个小人物
Are funerals entertainment?
会这样受欢迎？
- He's not going to show. - Show time is show time.
嘿，伙计，要上场了
This guy's done it to us too many times. We should go on without him.
外边的声音太大了 我们只有把节奏缓下来
Bill is with him. They're an hour away. He'll get him here, all right?
我知道，可是你别在这儿待得太久 知道吗？
He fucking better get him here, man.
-啊，我知道 -今天晚上的演出...
- Hey, he'll be here. - l'll tell you one goddamn thing.
不知能爆出什么样的冷门啊
There's gonna be a show here tonight if l gotta throw a wig on, man...
他们每演一次就轰动一回
and sing them songs myself.
是吗，真够刺激的
Yeah, fuck off.
是啊
How's it going?
你好
- Hey, dude. - Yo, Jimbo.
嘿，吉姆
- Clean up your act. - You asshole.
你好吗
l love you! Hey, listen, Paul.
谢谢，我爱你!
- Can you get us some heroin? - No.
-保罗，你来一点吧 -不
Why not? Some heroin.
为什么，就闻一下
l am not gonna participate in anything...
别的事都行
that's gonna help you accomplish your goal, Jim.
就这事不能通融，吉姆
What's my goal, Paul?
哦，保罗，你真不够朋友
Your only friend, the end
你够朋友
Wrong. l just want to sing the blues, man.
他很聪明，这家伙 又在那儿玩深沉了
Get fat, do nothin', go nowhere. Just be.
真笨，不懂得及时行乐 不明白这世上的一切只是过眼云烟
With that waistline, you ain't got much choice.
因此我们要抓住机会
What is wrong with being a large mammal?
要是成了一个巨大的贪欲之神
- A big beast, like a tank. - You're king crawling flab.
能够拥有一切的怪物 又会怎么样
Rock is cock, baby, and your rock is dying.
那是一切之王 坚如磐石呼风唤雨
Rock is death, man. There's no longer belief.
呼风唤雨 可惜如今没有人相信这样的东西了
l'll write poetry...
行了，整天和诗
and direct movies.
歌曲，电影打交道
That's bullshit.
烦死了
You tested all the limits-- fame, fucking...
这可是有能力的标志，老兄
money.
拥有荣誉，金钱，头衔
What you gonna do when the music's over, man...
领导音乐的潮流
when you're too fat and old to go out onstage?
难道你不想这样干下去吗？
What you gonna do for act three? Puke on heaven's door?
想成为一个三流演员 没有理会你的门吗？
Listen, you two-bit fucking actor.
听我说
You underestimate the audience.
可是这一切的答案都在哪儿呢
Face it, Jim. You're not gonna be remembered.
你知道我最后的结局会是什么
You think all they want is...
这得看你了，吉姆
two cars and a house.
你认为他们想要什么
But you're wrong.
两辆汽车和房子
- You know what they want? - No. Tell me.
你错了，你知道他们想要什么
- You really want to know? - Yeah, tell me. What?
-不，我不知道 -你肯定知道他们想要什么，我不知道
Something sacred.
神秘的东西
That's what they want.
他们想要神秘的东西
Something sacred.
神秘的东西
- He's two hours late! - Where the fuck are the seats?
让开，让开，让开，我们要进去演出
- l took them out. - How are you doin'?
不行，让我们进去
l'd like you to meet my new friend.
让开让开 真高兴能见到这么多的新朋友
- You're not playing, huh? - We're gonna sue your fucking ass.
-你开什么玩笑？  -先生 我们要进去演出，让我们进去
So sue me. lf you ain't playing, see where your equipment is tomorrow.
什么？说什么呀，先生 我们得立刻去见见你的经纪人
l'm not going out there until l get some sort of guarantee.
我们等到现在了
Come on, John. How will you know what could have been?
我以为你们不来了呢，你们这些混蛋 哎，伙计，伙计，你怎么知道我来不了
How will you know unless you break on through?
你怎么知道，去你的
Fucking asshole!
你忘了，你啊
You're pushing death, Morrison.
约翰，你真自私
People think we're drug addicts because of you.
吉姆，随你的便吧
- Are we the Beatles now, John? - We took drugs to expand our mind.
哦，哦，让开，让开，得了得了
- Not to escape. - Get him on the fucking stage!
不然我要闯过去了，啊
Listen.
听好了
Have you ever eaten human flesh?
我知道你有意见
'Cause l know this chick in New York, man.
算了吧，算了吧
Hey, it's cool.
罗比，罗比
Listen, listen.
过来，罗比
Just one more time, for old times' sake.
就试一次吧
- l don't want any. - You'll play like an orgasm.
为了门，啊，伙计
Trust me.
我们得齐心协力
You said you loved pain.
就这样
You run from it every chance you get.
讨厌，我以后再也不会这样了
Doors! Doors! Doors!
门!门!门!
Are you ready?
准备好了吗？
Back off!
退后!
l don't want to see any more of that shit!
你太放肆了!
l'll haul your ass in, pal.
把烟灭了
Hey, Jim!
嗨，吉姆!
Five to one, baby
“从五数到一”
One in five
“那就是五分之一”
No one here gets out alive now
“这里的人，没有一个能活着出去”
You get yours, baby
“你们有你们的下场”
l'll get mine
“我有我的下场”
Gonna make it, baby if we try
“如果尝试，就会成功”
The old get older
“老的事物，变得更老”
The young get stronger
“年轻的事物，变得更年轻”
May take a week and it may take longer
“只需要一周，或者更长的时间”
They got the guns but we got the numbers
“但他们拥有枪炮，我们只有人”
Gonna win, yeah We're takin' over
“我们会取胜的，我们要掌权”
Come on!
“来吧!”
Let me hear ya!
“让我听听你们的叫声”
Look at this beautiful living thing, man.
那个漂亮的女孩子说
You wouldn't eat my little friend, would you?
你不会离开我这些小朋友的
Come on, man.
伙计，你不会的吧
Love animals. Don't eat them!
别离开，别离开，别离开我们
l'd fuck her, but she's too young.
哦，知道了，先抱着他
Your ballroom days
“你的表演生涯”
Are over, baby
“都结束了”
Night is drawing near
“夜幕降临”
Shadows of the evening
“暮色苍茫”
Crawl across the year
“随着年轮慢慢弥散”
You walk across the floor
“你走过了地板”
With a flower in your hand
“手里拿着花朵”
Trying to tell me no one understands
“要告诉我，没有人理解你”
Trade in your house
“房子里面的买卖”
For a handful of dimes
“毒品啊，毒品”
Gonna make it, baby
“会成功的”
ln our prime
“趁我们还年轻”
Get together
“大家走在一起”
One more time
“再一次”
Get together
“走在一起”
One more time
“再一次”
You're all a bunch of fucking slaves!
姑娘们，我喜欢你们
How long you think it's going to last?
你们打算玩多久
How long are you gonna let 'em push you around?
别再犹豫了，我告诉你们
l'll tell you this.
这回我真的打算来个痛快淋漓
l'm gonna get my kicks before the whole shithouse goes up in flames.
姑娘们，我们现在就开始吧
All right.
好吧
"Light My Fire!" Come on, Jim!
演唱“点燃火焰”吧
Fuck you, man!
去你的吧
That's the word. That's the very little word.
这个世界，多么渺小的世界啊
Come on, let me hear it. All your little hatred.
来呀，让我们尽情地拥有这个世界
You'd all eat shit, wouldn't ya?
令世人感到震惊
Adolf Hitler is alive and well and living in Miami.
啊，迈阿密的观众 多么富有热情和生命力啊
l fucked her last night.
我爱你们
What are you gonna do about it?
Come on, come on, come on Come on and suck me, babe
“来吧，来吧，来吧，来替我吹箫”
Can't you see that l need some head
“我需要你来帮我口交”
What was that-- Wait a minute. Ah, bullshit!
“等等吧，操”
lt's fucked up, man. lt's all bullshit!
“我操，我操，我操操操”
lt's all fucked up. l'm coming out!
“都是混蛋，我来了”
Miami Beach, Florida, huh?
佛罗里达，多美的地方
Hey, l went to Florida State.
我也想住在佛罗里达
Then l got smart and moved to California.
我的小乐队在加利福尼亚
They're trying to change the world out there in California.
我也离不开加利福尼亚
No, l ain't talkin' about no revolution.
我打算找到一个解决办法
l'm talkin' about having a good time this summer.
今天在这里，我想要告诉你们的是 我的确非常非常的愉快
l'm talking about love your neighbor until it hurts.
我要对你们说，我真的完全投入了
Come on. How 'bout a little nakedness?
来呀，各位 让我们做个小小的游戏吧
Come on. Let's see some action out there.
开始吧
l'm talkin' about love, love, love.
让我们尽情地娱乐
l'm talkin' about you and me lovin'--
我要告诉你们大家 我爱你们，爱你们
Anybody gonna come up here and love my ass?
哦，真的，我要和你们分享这一切
Come on. l'm lonely up here.
快啊，各位请便吧
l love you!
我爱你
Come on, sweetheart. You want to see it?
姑娘们，让我们一起共享这一刻吧
Why don't l pull it out for you, shake it around a little bit?
让我们共享这一刻
Will that do it for ya?
我要大声叫喊了
All right, now. l'm gonna show it to you.
You see it?
我就想尝尝
Yeah, l saw it!
我看到了!
l wanna see some action out there!
就想尝尝越轨的滋味
No limits! No laws!
我就想尝尝越轨的滋味
You want to fuck? Come on up here!
现在，你们他妈的来呀来呀
- This is your show! Yeah! - Get off my stage, motherfucker!
No laws! No limits!
表演很出色，来呀
Yeah! Fuckin' rock god!
快来，快来!来呀!
Where's the guy with the penis? Where's that son of a bitch? Get back!
拦住，拦住，别让他们过来
Fat cat in a top hat
“戴帽子的肥猫”
Dead cat in a top hat
“戴帽子的死猫”
Suckin' on a young man's
“在年轻人的头上”
Love
“爱情”
Wishin' he could come, yeah
“希望他出现”
Suckin' on a soldier's brain
“吸干了士兵的脑髓”
Wishin' it would be the same
“这会是一样的吗？”
Dead rats See, you're an aristocrat
“死去的落魄之人，你是贵族吗？”
Well, that's crap
“废话”
You know, the day destroy the night
“日光，把夜晚摧毁”
Night divide the day
“夜晚，分隔了白天”
Try to run, try to hide
“跑啊，藏啊”
Break on through to the other side
“跑到另外一边”
Come on!
“来吧”
Chased our pleasures here
“追寻快乐”
Dug our treasures there
“发掘你的宝藏”
Can you still recall the time we cried
“还记得我们哭泣的时候吗”
Break on through to--
“打破了”
Mr. Morrison.
莫里森先生
You are charged with lewd behavior on four counts.
你被指控犯有四种罪行
Simulated masturbation...
1970年，达德郡法庭 装腔作势，引诱观众
public drunkenness...
当众酗酒
profanity...
语言淫秽
and public exposure.
当众暴露
How do you plead?
你有要辩护的吗？
The defendant pleads not guilty, Your Honor.
法官大人，我认为被告无罪
Then trial is set for the week--
请控方律师陈述理由
l want to bring to the jury's attention that there's playing now on Broadway...
我想将指控重点放在那场演出上
a musical called "Hair" where the actors disrobe...
被告人在演出现场利用煽动性的音乐
and appear naked on the stage.
以及在舞台上公开裸体 来达到所谓最危险的目的
- Objection. That's irrelevant. - Sustained.
-我反对，这些都是你的想象 -反对无效
Your Honor, how can you sustain that?
而你们大家都是有目共睹的
Stick to the facts.
我的指控全是事实
This is a major First Amendment violation...
你的这些夸张言词对我的当事人
by the politicians and the police of Miami.
已构成了一种人身侮辱
Every single witness they've brought here...
你所指控的每个单独罪状
has testified to not actually seeing my client's genitals...
在这里都是不成立的.因为事实上 我的当事人并没有干这些事
except one, who is related to the arresting officer.
请你不要感情用事
l tell you, if you convict on such lack of evidence...
因为事实胜于雄辩
l assure you that someday, somewhere in the still of the night...
你完全可以朝肮脏的事实方面去理解
you will wake up screaming.
然而我敢肯定总有一天，这一切 都会水落石出的，你知道吗，吉姆
Are you gonna get rid of it?
得了，你怎么不说话
Look.
噢
Wouldn't it be better to have a kid with someone who wanted to be its father?
他们如此戏弄我到底想干嘛
lt'd be a fucking genius. That's what it'd be.
算了吧，该轮到你了
You and me?
哦，孩子，我们还有上帝
The child would be a goddess...
我们不能
or a god.
太出格了
lt'd be a monster.
残酷的人
No. Look.
一点怜悯心也没有
l got this trial that's hanging on me.
我像个可怜的动物似的接受盘问审讯
l can't afford this. l don't want the responsibility.
我不想负这样的责任
You're a coward, just a little boy!
逞英雄，小孩子
The only way you can't afford it is emotionally!
你真是个小孩子
Those vows were forever in the goddess' sight!
你很快就会被人遗忘的 站在上帝这边才能永恒
"Death does not part, only lack of love."
不要走到另一个极端 否则会众叛亲离
Come on, Patricia.
我要树立起一座纪念碑
l was stoned.
在时间的长河中
lt seemed like a fun thing to do at the time.
证明我的伟大
Fuck you. l'm gonna have the kid.
做梦吧，我还想当国王呢
Well, then it will be your kid.
哦，那样的话我就会是你的国王了
But if you want the abortion, l'll be there with you.
你想要什么我就给你什么
- Oh, no, you won't. - Yes, l will.
哦，不，讨厌的家伙
Bullshit, Morrison! You know who you are!
你明白你是谁吗？
What difference does it make, you know?
哦，莫里森
You never pretended.
他们让你明白过你是谁吗？
l did.
嗯
Yeah, l don't even like kids, particularly.
你从不随大流
l don't want the other fuckin' thing either.
举止行为简直像个十足的孩子 我也再不愿到剧场去了
Well.
嗯
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
你的那些可爱的欲望
- Look at that stomach. - Come on, now.
-也得改改了 -哦，行了
Don't say these things.
我们现在别说这些了
James Douglas Morrison...
吉姆道格拉斯莫里森
l hereby sentence you...
你因犯有语言淫秽罪
to six months of hard labor in the Dade County jail.
当众暴露罪
And for public exposure...
以及酗酒罪
l'm sentencing you to 60 days of the same...
现在本庭判决你
after which you are to serve two years and four months...
两年零四个月的有期徒刑
of probationary time.
缓期执行
Your Honor, l have an appellate bond in the sum of $50,000 here.
法官大人，我以五万美元作担保
l ask that Mr. Morrison remain free, pending his appeal.
保释莫里森先生重获自由并撤销起诉
Everywhere, Jim-- Jacksonville, Dallas, even Kent State University canceled.
据杰克逊报道 莫里森已被大学除了名
The press for the first time turned against us. We're fucked.
由此看来 舆论第一次对他显示了力量
Pamela's called six times. Katherine, Patricia. Gayle's pregnant.
朱里盖尔斯认为，帕姆拉和 帕特丽西娅之间的愤怒始终难以了结
You gotta go to the dentist. Look, Jim.
双方都竭尽全力地粉饰自己 以便能战胜对方
Go home, get some sleep.
回家吧，去睡觉吧
- Wash your hair. - Take a bath too, man.
洗头，洗澡
- Jesus, this guy really despises you. - We weren't even invited to Woodstock.
吉姆，别担心，这帮人全是密探
Twenty other bands. Not us.
有什么好惊奇的
First Hendrix, now Janis.
有人爱他
Radio stations won't play us. Some big cities.
今天吉姆要想再回到 过去的辉煌的日子里
Philly, Cinci, Chicago, Detroit.
恐怕已不大可能了
We can drag this appeal out for years, keep you out of jail.
吉姆，别理会这帮饭桶的话 想开一点，吉姆
The F.B.l.'s behind it. They had memos on you in Phoenix.
吉姆自己断送了自己的前程
They extradited you to Miami.
人们对迈阿密的事件
A new image.
记忆忧新
Slow, quiet. The beard. The elder of the tribe.
人们还会慢慢地悄悄地接纳他 人们还会作出这种尝试的
Mine eyes have seen the glory of the coming of the Lord!
“我看到了上帝的来临”
The band you love to hate.
你们都爱这些吗？
Let's win there.
“我们会赢的”
lt was fun.
太棒了
l think l'm having a nervous breakdown.
我从精神上是不会屈服的
- Do you hear me? - Climb on the edge, baby.
"1970年，洛杉矶，夏特蒙特饭店"
"1970年，洛杉矶，夏特蒙特饭店" -莫里森，你在干什么？ -嗨，宝贝，我想要回我的青春"1970年，洛杉矶，夏特蒙特饭店"
- Do you hear me? - Climb on the edge, baby.
"1970年，洛杉矶，夏特蒙特饭店"
We're rolling, Jim.
-莫里森，你在干什么？ -嗨，宝贝，我想要回我的青春
约翰，你怎么会过得那么好-莫里森，你在干什么？ -嗨，宝贝，我想要回我的青春
约翰，你怎么会过得那么好
- Jump! - Let him dance a little bit.
约翰，你怎么会过得那么好约翰，你怎么会过得那么好
约翰，你怎么会过得那么好
l want you to come back in here this minute, Jim Morrison.
吉姆莫里森 我希望你赶快打消这个念头
l am not gonna kill myself for you.
我还不想让自 己痛苦
- Goddamn it, Jim! - Your whole life is bullshit!
吉姆，我跟你说
- Shut up! - You want me, come out and get me!
你们这帮混蛋，滚开，离我远点
Oh, no!
哦，你别这样
Jim, where are you-- Pam, get back inside!
你别这样
- l love you. - Come out here, honey.
-吉姆 -噢，宝贝
- Come on, baby. - Jim, give her your hand.
-来呀，来呀，宝贝 -不，你别这样
- She's gonna fall. - Once more with feeling.
我很清醒，别拉我
Take two.
天啊
- l don't want to die. - Man, we gotta finish it.
来啊，亲爱的
- We don't have an ending, Ray. - All the poetry has wolves in it.
我看见我，我的头发在燃烧
- The most beautiful-- - Come on, girl.
-吉姆 -别这样，太美了
l see your hair is burning
哦，真美
The most beautiful one of all...
围着火圈
dances in a ring of fire...
大家都在一块跳舞
then throws off a challenge with a shrug.
为了，为了表达，表达一种挑战性
That's my girl.
你是我的姑娘
Let's go. Let's leave this place.
哦，我们都离开这儿
Just you and me, baby.
我们离开这个地方，你快把我吓死了
We can, you know.
你能
Just one more step.
就只要跨出一步
l want to live!
哦，不，别别别，别这样
l want to live with you!
别这样，我爱你
All the poetry has wolves in it, Pam.
哦，力量无穷的吉姆
All but one.
想要的一切也不过如此
The most beautiful one of all.
可是再美的东西
l hope you go out smiling...
我喜欢你一直像一个睡梦中的孩子 那样微笑
like a child into the cool remnant of a dream.
男人的一生就为了寻求这一切
The angel man...
耀眼的成功
has finally claimed this benevolent soul.
只是转瞬即逝
Ophelia...
就好像
leaves sudden in silk.
昙花一现
Glory in dream.
男人们
Mad, stifled witness.
男人们渴望的是精力
All right!
嗨，你好啊，朋友
Hi, Dorothy. Oh, you cut your hair.
嗨，你好，桃乐茜，把头发剪掉了
- We're trying to have another baby. - Was your hair getting in the way?
-是啊，你看我要照顾那些孩子 -难道你的头发挡住了你的路吗？
Where's Ray? l got to catch a plane.
我那帮兄弟们在那儿
He's upstairs.
在楼上
- Where's Princess? - Out back.
-我还想要杯酒 -我一会儿就送去
We added a rain effect to "Riders," man.
伙计们，我们这个小团体
lt's great.
很了不起
lt's the best album since "Days," man.
怎么都不说话
l must admit it's pretty good...
的确演了不少，不赖
for four guys who weren't even talking to each other that day.
真的很不错，我都不知道应该 对你们各位说些什么好了
So you're really gonna live in Paris, huh, man?
你真的要去巴黎吗？
Yeah. You know, be anonymous, write a book.
是啊，你怎么知道的
"Observations of an American While On Trial in Miami."
你可以写一本书 <美国人的观察，迈阿密的尝试>
Still got a lot of good songs in you.
伙计，还是写首歌吧
Still think we got a couple of blues albums in us.
你可以在歌中掺一些忧郁的成分
l'm pinned, man.
是可以，老兄
They got a category for everything we do.
你总有些
l'm a wanted man.
越轨的想法
l'm gonna miss you, man.
好，吉姆，我打算
l'm gonna miss that feeling of playing music with you, man.
去为电影配乐
You, John, miss me?
约翰，你喜欢上电影了
More than you think, asshole.
全是些新想法
Yeah.
好吧
You can always whip the horses' eyes.
仁者见仁，智者见智
As far as l'm concerned...
我觉得
l made music with Dionysus.
我们那种音乐要搞下去很困难
We had moments onstage that no one will ever fucking know.
我，不打算再干下去了
You lay off those drugs, Robby.
罗比，我看你还是别干这行了
Hey, Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
We'll get together again, you know...
什么时候我们还能再见
in some strange way.
真有些不可思议
Maybe we'll make a movie together. Black and white.
你们将来可以就此拍部电影
Sabrina, this is for you.
你拿着这个，这个给你
- Morrison, see you around. - What, no bon voyage?
吉姆，你有什么事吗？
l'll see you back.
我一会儿来看你
And little Princess Smiling Face...
一个小朋友在向你微笑
this one's for you...
这个给你
from Chief Mojo Rising.
多好看哪
Happy birthday, Princess.
生日快乐
- Let me see. - lt's you.
这是你
Forever young.
永远年轻
The strangest life l've ever known.
永远不可思议
Jim. You got a plane to catch, man?
吉姆，大伙开始演出了
Yeah.
是啊，是啊
We're reaching for death on the end of a candle.
就像蜡烛的尽头正向死亡迈进
We're trying for something that's already found us.
我们仍然在努力 寻求那早已存在的东西
Last words.
发出最后的声音
Out.
出去了
Did you get all that?
你们准备好了吗？
Yeah.
是的
l got it, Jim.
准备好了
Come on. Let's get some tacos.
让我们再次沉浸在音乐中吧
1971年，巴黎
Death.
死亡
lt's not so bad.
对人来说是
- Jim? - l love my girl.
最好不过的事了
Jim, is that you?
吉姆，是你吗？
l knew it was you, Jim Morrison. l always know when it's you.
我知道肯定是你，我知道是你
Come on, baby. Get out of the tub.
好了，乖孩子
Come on. Mama will dry you off.
把水龙头关上吧
Just stop joking around, you hear me? Just cut it out.
来吧，妈妈会帮你擦干的
Was it all right, Jim?
别开玩笑了，你听见我的话了吗？
Did you enjoy it when it came...
这下你该高兴了吧？
just like you said you would?
别再开玩笑了
拉雪兹公墓
乔治比才
莎拉伯恩哈特
They are waiting to take us...
人们都在等待
into the severed garden.
终有一天会走进那座坟
You know how pale and wanton thrillful comes death...
伙伴们呼唤这个奇妙的灵魂复活
in the strange hour...
宣称是他们
unannounced, unplanned for...
发现了这块瑰宝
like a scary, over-friendly guest you've brought to bed.
他毫不恐惧，坦然的走向死亡
Death makes angels of us all and give us wings...
他变成了天使，轻盈地飘过人间
where we had shoulders smooth as ravens' claws.
不再有金钱，也不再有优质大麻
No more money, no more fancy dress.
在另外一个王国中
This other kingdom seems by far the best...
继续干其他的事情，余下的人们 生活将刻板而单调
until its other jaw reveals incest...
女人和姑娘们
and loose obedience to a vegetable law.
会永远怀念
l will not go.
她们曾经拥有过的
l prefer a feast of friends to the giant family.
亲切的歌声
吉姆据说死于心力衰竭 时年27岁
3年后帕姆拉亦随他而去
时间轴调整、中英字幕合并@致远淡泊